{
  "metadata": {
    "source_file": "BAJHLIP23020V012223.pdf",
    "policy_number": "look",
    "effective_date": null,
    "coverage_types": [
      "health",
      "accident",
      "property",
      "liability"
    ],
    "file_info": {
      "path": "G:\\project\\life_insurence_query\\file_inputs\\BAJHLIP23020V012223.pdf",
      "last_modified": "2025-07-25 15:55:19.278732"
    }
  },
  "clauses": [
    {
      "text": "Bajaj Allianz General Insurance Co. Ltd.\nBajaj Allianz House, Airport Road, Yerawada, Pune - 411 006. Reg. No.: 113\nFor more details, log on to: www.bajajallianz.com | E-mail: bagichelp@bajajallianz.co.in or\nCall at: Sales - 1800 209 0144 / Service - 1800 209 5858 (Toll Free No.)\nIssuing Office: GLOBAL HEALTH CARE\nPolicy Wordings\nUIN- BAJHLIP23020V012223",
      "type": "GENERAL",
      "subtypes": [],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz General Insurance Co. Ltd.",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 40
        },
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz House",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 41,
          "end": 60
        },
        {
          "text": "Airport Road",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 62,
          "end": 74
        },
        {
          "text": "Yerawada",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 76,
          "end": 84
        },
        {
          "text": "Pune",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 86,
          "end": 90
        },
        {
          "text": "113",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 112,
          "end": 115
        },
        {
          "text": "bagichelp@bajajallianz.co.in",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 176,
          "end": 204
        },
        {
          "text": "Sales - 1800",
          "type": "EVENT",
          "start": 217,
          "end": 229
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "SECTION A) PREAMBLE\nWhereas the Insured described in the Policy Schedule hereto (hereinafter called the ‘Insured’ or “Policyholder” or\n“Insured Person”) has made to Bajaj Allianz General Insurance Company Limited (hereinafter called the “Company”\nor “Insurer” or “Insurance Company”) a proposal or Proposal as mentioned in the transcript of the Proposal, which\nshall be the basis of this Contract and is deemed to be incorporated herein, containing certain undertakings,\ndeclarations, information/particulars and statements, which is hereby agreed to be the basis of this Contract and be\nconsidered as incorporated herein, for the insurance Contract hereinafter contained and has paid the premium\nspecified in the Policy Schedule hereto as consideration for such insurance Contract, now the Company agrees,\nsubject always to the Policy Schedule and the following terms, conditions, exclusions, and limitations of the Policy,",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "the ‘Insured’ or “",
          "type": "LAW",
          "start": 100,
          "end": 118
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured Person",
          "type": "WORK_OF_ART",
          "start": 136,
          "end": 150
        },
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz General Insurance Company Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 165,
          "end": 212
        },
        {
          "text": "Proposal",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 298,
          "end": 306
        },
        {
          "text": "Proposal",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 345,
          "end": 353
        },
        {
          "text": "Company",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 791,
          "end": 798
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Schedule",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 825,
          "end": 844
        },
        {
          "text": "Policy",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 917,
          "end": 923
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "subject always to the Policy Schedule and the following terms, conditions, exclusions, and limitations of the Policy,\nand in excess of the amount of the Deductible/Co-Payment, to indemnify the Insured in respect of an admissible\nclaim in the manner and to the extent hereinafter stated.",
      "type": "EXCLUSION",
      "subtypes": [],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "the Policy Schedule",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 18,
          "end": 37
        },
        {
          "text": "the Deductible/Co-Payment",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 149,
          "end": 174
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.0
    },
    {
      "text": "SECTION B) DEFINITIONS - STANDARD DEFINITIONS\nWords or terms mentioned below have the meaning ascribed to them wherever they appear in this Policy, and\nreferences to the singular or to the masculine, include references to the plural or to the feminine wherever the context\npermits. If any word starts with Capital alphabet but is not defined in the Standard Definitions or Specific Definitions,\nthen such word shall be interpreted as per the headings of the respective clauses/points in these Policy Wordings.",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Policy",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 140,
          "end": 146
        },
        {
          "text": "Capital alphabet",
          "type": "LOC",
          "start": 306,
          "end": 322
        },
        {
          "text": "Policy Wordings",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 493,
          "end": 508
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "1. Accident:-\nAn Accident means sudden, unforeseen and involuntary event caused by external, visible and violent means.",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "1",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 1
        },
        {
          "text": "Accident",
          "type": "LOC",
          "start": 17,
          "end": 25
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "2. Any one Illness:-\nAny one Illness means continuous Period of Illness and it includes relapse within 45 days from the date of last\nconsultation with the Hospital/Nursing Home where treatment was taken.",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 1
        },
        {
          "text": "one",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 7,
          "end": 10
        },
        {
          "text": "Illness:-",
          "type": "NORP",
          "start": 11,
          "end": 20
        },
        {
          "text": "one",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 25,
          "end": 28
        },
        {
          "text": "45 days",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 103,
          "end": 110
        },
        {
          "text": "the date of last",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 116,
          "end": 132
        },
        {
          "text": "the Hospital/Nursing Home",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 151,
          "end": 176
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "3. AYUSH Hospital:-\nAn AYUSH Hospital is a healthcare facility wherein medical/surgical/para-surgical treatment procedures and\ninterventions are carried out by AYUSH Medical Practitioner(s) comprising of any of the following:\na. Central or State Government AYUSH Hospital; or\nb. Teaching Hospital attached to AYUSH College recognized by the Central Government/Central Council of\nIndian Medicine/Central Council for Homeopathy; or\nc. AYUSH Hospital, standalone or co-located with Inpatient healthcare facility of any recognized system of\nmedicine, registered with the local authorities, wherever applicable, and is under the supervision of a qualified\nregistered AYUSH Medical Practitioner and must comply with all the following criterion:\ni. Having at least 5 Inpatient beds;\nii. Having qualified AYUSH Medical Practitioner in charge round the clock;\niii. Having dedicated AYUSH therapy sections as required and/or has equipped operation theatre where\nsurgical procedures are to be carried out;",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "3",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 1
        },
        {
          "text": "Practitioner(s",
          "type": "NORP",
          "start": 174,
          "end": 188
        },
        {
          "text": "State Government AYUSH Hospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 240,
          "end": 271
        },
        {
          "text": "b. Teaching Hospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 276,
          "end": 296
        },
        {
          "text": "AYUSH College",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 309,
          "end": 322
        },
        {
          "text": "the Central Government/Central Council",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 337,
          "end": 375
        },
        {
          "text": "Indian Medicine/Central Council",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 379,
          "end": 410
        },
        {
          "text": "Homeopathy",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 415,
          "end": 425
        },
        {
          "text": "c. AYUSH Hospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 430,
          "end": 447
        },
        {
          "text": "at least 5",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 749,
          "end": 759
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "iii. Having dedicated AYUSH therapy sections as required and/or has equipped operation theatre where\nsurgical procedures are to be carried out;\niv.Maintaining daily records of the patients and making them accessible to the Insurance Company’s\nauthorized representative.\n4. AYUSH Day Care Centre:-\nAYUSH Day Care Centre means and includes Community Health Centre (CHC), Primary Health Centre (PHC),\nDispensary, Clinic, Polyclinic or any such health centre which is registered with the local authorities, wherever\napplicable and having facilities for carrying out treatment procedures and medical or surgical/para-surgical\ninterventions or both under the supervision of registered AYUSH Medical Practitioner (s) on Day Care Treatment\nbasis without Inpatient services and must comply with all the following criterion:\ni. Having qualified registered AYUSH Medical Practitioner(s) in charge;\nii. Having dedicated AYUSH therapy sections as required and/or has equipped operation theatre where",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "daily",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 159,
          "end": 164
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insurance Company’s",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 219,
          "end": 242
        },
        {
          "text": "4",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 270,
          "end": 271
        },
        {
          "text": "Community Health Centre",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 338,
          "end": 361
        },
        {
          "text": "CHC",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 363,
          "end": 366
        },
        {
          "text": "Primary Health Centre",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 369,
          "end": 390
        },
        {
          "text": "PHC",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 392,
          "end": 395
        },
        {
          "text": "Clinic",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 410,
          "end": 416
        },
        {
          "text": "Polyclinic",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 418,
          "end": 428
        },
        {
          "text": "Practitioner(s",
          "type": "NORP",
          "start": 860,
          "end": 874
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "ii. Having dedicated AYUSH therapy sections as required and/or has equipped operation theatre where\nsurgical procedures are to be carried out;\niii. Maintaining daily records of the patients and making them accessible to the Insurance Company’s\nauthorized representative.\nUIN- BAJHLIP23020V012223 Global Health Care/ Policy Wordings/Page 1\nBajaj Allianz General Insurance Co. Ltd.\nBajaj Allianz House, Airport Road, Yerawada, Pune - 411 006. Reg. No.: 113\nFor more details, log on to: www.bajajallianz.com | E-mail: bagichelp@bajajallianz.co.in or\nCall at: Sales - 1800 209 0144 / Service - 1800 209 5858 (Toll Free No.)\nIssuing Office: GLOBAL HEALTH CARE\n5. Cashless Facility:-\nCashless Facility means a facility extended by the Insurer to the Insured where the payments, of the costs of\ntreatment undergone by the Insured in accordance with the Policy terms and conditions, are directly made to the\nNetwork Provider by the Insurer to the extent pre-authorization is approved.",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "daily",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 160,
          "end": 165
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insurance Company’s",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 220,
          "end": 243
        },
        {
          "text": "Global Health Care/",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 296,
          "end": 315
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 337,
          "end": 338
        },
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz General Insurance Co. Ltd.",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 339,
          "end": 379
        },
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz House",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 380,
          "end": 399
        },
        {
          "text": "Airport Road",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 401,
          "end": 413
        },
        {
          "text": "Yerawada",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 415,
          "end": 423
        },
        {
          "text": "Pune",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 425,
          "end": 429
        },
        {
          "text": "113",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 451,
          "end": 454
        },
        {
          "text": "bagichelp@bajajallianz.co.in",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 515,
          "end": 543
        },
        {
          "text": "Sales - 1800",
          "type": "EVENT",
          "start": 556,
          "end": 568
        },
        {
          "text": "5",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 655,
          "end": 656
        },
        {
          "text": "Cashless Facility",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 678,
          "end": 695
        },
        {
          "text": "Insurer",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 729,
          "end": 736
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 744,
          "end": 751
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 815,
          "end": 822
        },
        {
          "text": "Network Provider",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 900,
          "end": 916
        },
        {
          "text": "Insurer",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 924,
          "end": 931
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "Network Provider by the Insurer to the extent pre-authorization is approved.\n6. Condition Precedent:-\nCondition Precedent means a Policy term or condition upon which the Insurer's liability under the Policy is\nconditional upon.\n7. Congenital Anomaly:-\nCongenital Anomaly means a condition which is present since birth, and which is abnormal with reference to\nform, structure or position.\na. Internal Congenital Anomaly- Congenital Anomaly which is not in the visible and accessible parts of the body\nb. External Congenital Anomaly- Congenital Anomaly which is in the visible and accessible parts of the body\n8. Co-Payment:-\nA Co-Payment means a cost-sharing requirement under a health insurance Policy that provides that the\nPolicyholder/Insured will bear a specified percentage of the admissible claim amount. A Co-Payment does not\nreduce the Sum Insured.\n9. Cumulative Bonus:-\nCumulative Bonus means any increase or addition in the Sum Insured granted by the insurer without an",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Network Provider",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 16
        },
        {
          "text": "Insurer",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 24,
          "end": 31
        },
        {
          "text": "6",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 77,
          "end": 78
        },
        {
          "text": "Insurer",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 170,
          "end": 177
        },
        {
          "text": "7",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 228,
          "end": 229
        },
        {
          "text": "8",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 608,
          "end": 609
        },
        {
          "text": "Policyholder/Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 725,
          "end": 745
        },
        {
          "text": "9",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 857,
          "end": 858
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "reduce the Sum Insured.\n9. Cumulative Bonus:-\nCumulative Bonus means any increase or addition in the Sum Insured granted by the insurer without an\nassociated increase in premium.\n10. Day Care Centre:-\nA Day Care Centre means any institution established for Day Care Treatment of Illness and / or injuries or a\nmedical set -up with a Hospital and which has been registered with the local authorities, wherever applicable, and\nis under supervision of a registered and qualified Medical Practitioner AND must comply with all minimum\ncriterion as under:-\ni. has qualified nursing staff under its employment;\nii. has qualified Medical Practitioner (s) in charge;\niii. has a fully equipped operation theatre of its own where surgical procedures are carried out;\niv. maintains daily records of patients and will make these accessible to the Insurance Company’s authorized\npersonnel.\n11. Day Care Treatment:-\nDay care treatment means medical treatment, and/or surgical procedure which is:",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "9",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 24,
          "end": 25
        },
        {
          "text": "10",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 179,
          "end": 181
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 333,
          "end": 341
        },
        {
          "text": "Medical Practitioner",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 622,
          "end": 642
        },
        {
          "text": "daily",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 770,
          "end": 775
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insurance Company’s",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 830,
          "end": 853
        },
        {
          "text": "11",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 876,
          "end": 878
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "personnel.\n11. Day Care Treatment:-\nDay care treatment means medical treatment, and/or surgical procedure which is:\ni. undertaken under General or Local Anesthesia in a Hospital/Day Care Centre in less than 24 hrs because of\ntechnological advancement, and\nii. Which would have otherwise required a Hospitalization of more than 24 hours.\nTreatment normally taken on an out-patient basis is not included in the scope of this definition.\n12. Deductible:-\nDeductible means a cost sharing requirement under a health insurance Policy that provides that the insurer will\nnot be liable for a specified amount in case of indemnity policies and for a specified number of days/hours in case\nof Hospital cash policies which will apply before any benefits are payable by the insurer. A Deductible does not\nreduce the Sum Insured.\n13. Dental Treatment:-\nDental Treatment means a treatment related to teeth or structures supporting teeth including examinations, fillings",
      "type": "COVERAGE",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "COVERAGE"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "11",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 11,
          "end": 13
        },
        {
          "text": "less than 24 hrs",
          "type": "TIME",
          "start": 197,
          "end": 213
        },
        {
          "text": "24 hours",
          "type": "TIME",
          "start": 327,
          "end": 335
        },
        {
          "text": "12",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 435,
          "end": 437
        },
        {
          "text": "days/hours",
          "type": "TIME",
          "start": 661,
          "end": 671
        },
        {
          "text": "Deductible",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 773,
          "end": 783
        },
        {
          "text": "13",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 817,
          "end": 819
        },
        {
          "text": "Dental",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 821,
          "end": 827
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.6666666666666666
    },
    {
      "text": "13. Dental Treatment:-\nDental Treatment means a treatment related to teeth or structures supporting teeth including examinations, fillings\n(where appropriate), crowns, extractions and surgery.\n14. Disclosure to information norm:-\nThe Policy shall be void and all premium paid thereon shall be forfeited to the Company, in the event of\nmisrepresentation, mis-description or non-disclosure of any material fact.\n15. Emergency Care:-\nEmergency care means management for an Illness or Injury which results in symptoms which occur suddenly and\nunexpectedly, and requires immediate care by a Medical Practitioner to prevent death or serious long term\nimpairment of the Insured person’s health.\nUIN- BAJHLIP23020V012223 Global Health Care/ Policy Wordings/Page 2\nBajaj Allianz General Insurance Co. Ltd.\nBajaj Allianz House, Airport Road, Yerawada, Pune - 411 006. Reg. No.: 113\nFor more details, log on to: www.bajajallianz.com | E-mail: bagichelp@bajajallianz.co.in or",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "13",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 2
        },
        {
          "text": "Dental",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 4,
          "end": 10
        },
        {
          "text": "14",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 193,
          "end": 195
        },
        {
          "text": "Company",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 310,
          "end": 317
        },
        {
          "text": "15",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 410,
          "end": 412
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 663,
          "end": 670
        },
        {
          "text": "Global Health Care/",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 713,
          "end": 732
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 754,
          "end": 755
        },
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz General Insurance Co. Ltd.",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 756,
          "end": 796
        },
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz House",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 797,
          "end": 816
        },
        {
          "text": "Airport Road",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 818,
          "end": 830
        },
        {
          "text": "Yerawada",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 832,
          "end": 840
        },
        {
          "text": "Pune",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 842,
          "end": 846
        },
        {
          "text": "113",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 868,
          "end": 871
        },
        {
          "text": "bagichelp@bajajallianz.co.in",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 932,
          "end": 960
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.0
    },
    {
      "text": "For more details, log on to: www.bajajallianz.com | E-mail: bagichelp@bajajallianz.co.in or\nCall at: Sales - 1800 209 0144 / Service - 1800 209 5858 (Toll Free No.)\nIssuing Office: GLOBAL HEALTH CARE\n16. Grace Period:-\nGrace period means the specified period of time immediately following the premium due date during which a\npayment can be made to renew or continue a Policy in force without loss of continuity benefits such as waiting\nperiods and coverage of pre-existing diseases. Coverage is not available for the period for which no premium is\nreceived.\n17. Hospital:-\nA Hospital means any institution established for Inpatient care and Day Care Treatment of Illness and/or injuries\nand which has been registered as a Hospital with the local authorities under the Clinical Establishments\n(Registration and Regulation) Act, 2010 OR under the enactments specified under the Schedule of Section 56(1)\nof the said Act OR complies with all minimum criteria as under:",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "bagichelp@bajajallianz.co.in",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 60,
          "end": 88
        },
        {
          "text": "Sales - 1800",
          "type": "EVENT",
          "start": 101,
          "end": 113
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 200,
          "end": 202
        },
        {
          "text": "Grace Period:-\nGrace",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 204,
          "end": 224
        },
        {
          "text": "17",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 558,
          "end": 560
        },
        {
          "text": "Registration and Regulation",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 793,
          "end": 820
        },
        {
          "text": "2010",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 827,
          "end": 831
        },
        {
          "text": "the Schedule of Section 56(1",
          "type": "LAW",
          "start": 872,
          "end": 900
        },
        {
          "text": "Act",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 914,
          "end": 917
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "of the said Act OR complies with all minimum criteria as under:\ni. has qualified nursing staff under its employment round the clock;\nii. has at least 10 Inpatient beds in towns having a population of less than 10,00,000 and at least 15 Inpatient\nbeds in all other places;\niii. has qualified Medical Practitioner(s) in charge round the clock;\niv. has a fully equipped operation theatre of its own where surgical procedures are carried out;\nv. maintains daily records of patients and makes these accessible to the Insurance Company’s authorized\npersonnel.\n18. Hospitalization:-\nHospitalization means admission in a Hospital for a minimum period of 24 consecutive In-patient Care hours\nexcept for specified procedures/ treatments, where such admission could be for a period of less than 24\nconsecutive hours.\n19. Illness:-\nIllness means a sickness or a disease or pathological condition leading to the impairment of normal physiological\nfunction and requires medical treatment.",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Act",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 12,
          "end": 15
        },
        {
          "text": "at least 10",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 141,
          "end": 152
        },
        {
          "text": "less than 10,00,000",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 200,
          "end": 219
        },
        {
          "text": "at least 15",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 224,
          "end": 235
        },
        {
          "text": "Practitioner(s",
          "type": "NORP",
          "start": 299,
          "end": 313
        },
        {
          "text": "daily",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 452,
          "end": 457
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insurance Company’s",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 508,
          "end": 531
        },
        {
          "text": "18",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 554,
          "end": 556
        },
        {
          "text": "24",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 646,
          "end": 648
        },
        {
          "text": "hours",
          "type": "TIME",
          "start": 677,
          "end": 682
        },
        {
          "text": "less than",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 774,
          "end": 783
        },
        {
          "text": "19",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 806,
          "end": 808
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "function and requires medical treatment.\na. Acute condition - Acute condition is a disease, Illness or Injury that is likely to respond quickly to treatment\nwhich aims to return the person to his or her state of health immediately before suffering the\ndisease/Illness/Injury which leads to full recovery.\nb. Chronic condition – A chronic condition is defined as a disease, Illness, or Injury that has one or more of the\nfollowing characteristics:\na. it needs ongoing or long-term monitoring through consultations, examinations, check-ups, and /or tests\nb. it needs ongoing or long-term control for relief of symptoms\nc. it requires rehabilitation for the patient or for the patient to be specially trained to cope with it\nd. it continues indefinitely\ne. it recurs or is likely to recur.\n20. Injury:-\nInjury means Accidental physical bodily harm excluding Illness or disease solely and directly caused by external,",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Injury",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 385,
          "end": 391
        },
        {
          "text": "one",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 401,
          "end": 404
        },
        {
          "text": "20",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 787,
          "end": 789
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.0
    },
    {
      "text": "20. Injury:-\nInjury means Accidental physical bodily harm excluding Illness or disease solely and directly caused by external,\nviolent, visible and evident means which is verified and certified by a Medical Practitioner.\n21. Inpatient Care:-\nInpatient care means treatment for which the Insured has to stay in a Hospital for more than 24 hours for a\ncovered event.\n22. Intensive Care Unit:-\nIntensive Care Unit means an identified section, ward or wing of a Hospital which is under the constant\nsupervision of a dedicated Medical Practitioner(s), and which is specially equipped for the continuous monitoring\nand treatment of patients who are in a critical condition, or require life support facilities and where the level of care\nand supervision is considerably more sophisticated and intensive than in the ordinary and other wards.\n23. ICU Charges:-\nICU (Intensive Care Unit) Charges means the amount charged by a Hospital towards ICU expenses which shall",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION",
        "COVERAGE"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "20",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 2
        },
        {
          "text": "21",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 221,
          "end": 223
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 287,
          "end": 294
        },
        {
          "text": "more than 24 hours",
          "type": "TIME",
          "start": 325,
          "end": 343
        },
        {
          "text": "22",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 365,
          "end": 367
        },
        {
          "text": "Intensive Care Unit:-",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 369,
          "end": 390
        },
        {
          "text": "Practitioner(s",
          "type": "NORP",
          "start": 530,
          "end": 544
        },
        {
          "text": "23",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 834,
          "end": 836
        },
        {
          "text": "Intensive Care Unit)",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 857,
          "end": 877
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "23. ICU Charges:-\nICU (Intensive Care Unit) Charges means the amount charged by a Hospital towards ICU expenses which shall\ninclude the expenses for ICU bed, general medical support services provided to any ICU patient including\nmonitoring devices, critical care nursing and intensivist charges.\n24. Kidney Failure Requiring Regular Dialysis:-\nEnd stage renal disease presenting as chronic irreversible failure of both kidneys to function, as a result\nof which either regular renal dialysis (hemodialysis or peritoneal dialysis) is instituted or renal transplantation is\ncarried out. Diagnosis has to be confirmed by a Specialist Medical Practitioner.\nUIN- BAJHLIP23020V012223 Global Health Care/ Policy Wordings/Page 3\nBajaj Allianz General Insurance Co. Ltd.\nBajaj Allianz House, Airport Road, Yerawada, Pune - 411 006. Reg. No.: 113\nFor more details, log on to: www.bajajallianz.com | E-mail: bagichelp@bajajallianz.co.in or",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "23",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 2
        },
        {
          "text": "Intensive Care Unit)",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 23,
          "end": 43
        },
        {
          "text": "ICU",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 149,
          "end": 152
        },
        {
          "text": "ICU",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 207,
          "end": 210
        },
        {
          "text": "24",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 296,
          "end": 298
        },
        {
          "text": "a Specialist Medical Practitioner",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 617,
          "end": 650
        },
        {
          "text": "Global Health Care/",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 677,
          "end": 696
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 718,
          "end": 719
        },
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz General Insurance Co. Ltd.",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 720,
          "end": 760
        },
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz House",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 761,
          "end": 780
        },
        {
          "text": "Airport Road",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 782,
          "end": 794
        },
        {
          "text": "Yerawada",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 796,
          "end": 804
        },
        {
          "text": "Pune",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 806,
          "end": 810
        },
        {
          "text": "113",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 832,
          "end": 835
        },
        {
          "text": "bagichelp@bajajallianz.co.in",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 896,
          "end": 924
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.0
    },
    {
      "text": "For more details, log on to: www.bajajallianz.com | E-mail: bagichelp@bajajallianz.co.in or\nCall at: Sales - 1800 209 0144 / Service - 1800 209 5858 (Toll Free No.)\nIssuing Office: GLOBAL HEALTH CARE\n25. Maternity expenses:-\nMaternity expenses means;\na. medical treatment expenses traceable to childbirth (including complicated deliveries and caesarean sections\nincurred during Hospitalization);\nb. expenses towards lawful medical termination of pregnancy during the Policy Period.\n26. Medical Advice:-\nMedical Advice means any consultation or advice from a Medical Practitioner including the issuance of any\nprescription or follow up prescription.\n27. Medical Expenses:-\nMedical Expenses means those expenses that an Insured has necessarily and actually incurred for medical\ntreatment on account of Illness or Accident on the advice of a Medical Practitioner, as long as these are no more\nthan would have been payable if the Insured had not been Insured and no more than other Hospitals or Medical",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION",
        "COVERAGE"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "bagichelp@bajajallianz.co.in",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 60,
          "end": 88
        },
        {
          "text": "Sales - 1800",
          "type": "EVENT",
          "start": 101,
          "end": 113
        },
        {
          "text": "25",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 200,
          "end": 202
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Period",
          "type": "LAW",
          "start": 463,
          "end": 480
        },
        {
          "text": "26",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 482,
          "end": 484
        },
        {
          "text": "Medical Advice",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 503,
          "end": 517
        },
        {
          "text": "Medical Practitioner",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 558,
          "end": 578
        },
        {
          "text": "27",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 649,
          "end": 651
        },
        {
          "text": "Medical Expenses:-\nMedical Expenses",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 653,
          "end": 688
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 718,
          "end": 725
        },
        {
          "text": "Accident",
          "type": "LOC",
          "start": 811,
          "end": 819
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 926,
          "end": 933
        },
        {
          "text": "Medical",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 991,
          "end": 998
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "than would have been payable if the Insured had not been Insured and no more than other Hospitals or Medical\nPractitioners in the same locality would have charged for the same medical treatment.\n28. Medical Practitioner/Doctor/ Physician:-\nMedical Practitioner means a person who holds a valid registration from the Medical Council of any State or\nMedical Council of India or Council for Indian Medicine or for Homeopathy set up by the Government of India or a\nState Government and is thereby entitled to practice medicine within its jurisdiction; and is acting within its scope\nand jurisdiction of license.\n29. Medically Necessary Treatment:-\nMedically necessary treatment means any treatment, tests, medication, or stay in Hospital or part of a stay in\nHospital which:\ni. is required for the medical management of the Illness or Injury suffered by the Insured;\nii. must not exceed the level of care necessary to provide safe, adequate and appropriate medical care in\nscope, duration, or intensity;",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION",
        "COVERAGE"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 36,
          "end": 43
        },
        {
          "text": "28",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 195,
          "end": 197
        },
        {
          "text": "Medical Practitioner",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 240,
          "end": 260
        },
        {
          "text": "the Medical Council of any State",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 312,
          "end": 344
        },
        {
          "text": "Medical Council of India",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 348,
          "end": 372
        },
        {
          "text": "Council for Indian Medicine",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 376,
          "end": 403
        },
        {
          "text": "Homeopathy",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 411,
          "end": 421
        },
        {
          "text": "the Government of India",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 432,
          "end": 455
        },
        {
          "text": "29",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 608,
          "end": 610
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 725,
          "end": 733
        },
        {
          "text": "the Illness or Injury",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 816,
          "end": 837
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 854,
          "end": 861
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "ii. must not exceed the level of care necessary to provide safe, adequate and appropriate medical care in\nscope, duration, or intensity;\niii. must have been prescribed by a Medical Practitioner,\niv. must conform to the professional standards widely accepted in international medical practice or by the\nmedical community in India.\n30. Migration:-\nMigration means, the right accorded to health insurance policyholders (including all members under family cover\nand members under family cover and members of group health insurance Policy), to transfer the credit gained for\npre-existing conditions and time bound exclusions, with the same insurer.\n31. Network Provider:-\nNetwork Provider means Hospitals or health care providers enlisted by an insurer, TPA or jointly by an Insurer\nand TPA to provide medical services to an Insured by a Cashless Facility.\n32. New Born Baby:-\nNew Born Baby means baby born during the Policy Period and is aged up to 90 days.\n33. Non- Network Provider:-",
      "type": "LIMITATION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION",
        "LIMITATION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 323,
          "end": 328
        },
        {
          "text": "30",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 330,
          "end": 332
        },
        {
          "text": "31",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 644,
          "end": 646
        },
        {
          "text": "Network Provider",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 667,
          "end": 683
        },
        {
          "text": "Insurer",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 770,
          "end": 777
        },
        {
          "text": "Cashless Facility",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 833,
          "end": 850
        },
        {
          "text": "32",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 852,
          "end": 854
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Period",
          "type": "LAW",
          "start": 909,
          "end": 926
        },
        {
          "text": "up to 90 days",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 939,
          "end": 952
        },
        {
          "text": "33",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 954,
          "end": 956
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.0
    },
    {
      "text": "32. New Born Baby:-\nNew Born Baby means baby born during the Policy Period and is aged up to 90 days.\n33. Non- Network Provider:-\nNon-Network Provider means any Hospital, Day Care Centre or other provider that is not part of the Network.\n34. Notification of Claim:-\nNotification of claim means the process of intimating a claim to the insurer or TPA through any of the recognized\nmodes of communication.\n35. OPD treatment:-\nOPD treatment means the one in which the Insured visits a clinic / Hospital or associated facility like a\nconsultation room for diagnosis and treatment based on the advice of a Medical Practitioner. The Insured is not\nadmitted as a Day Care Treatment or Inpatient.\n36. Portability:-\nPortability means the right accorded to an individual health insurance policyholder (including all members\nunder family cover) to transfer the credit gained for pre-existing conditions and time-bound exclusions from\none insurer to another.",
      "type": "LIMITATION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "LIMITATION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "32",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 2
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Period",
          "type": "LAW",
          "start": 57,
          "end": 74
        },
        {
          "text": "up to 90 days",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 87,
          "end": 100
        },
        {
          "text": "33",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 102,
          "end": 104
        },
        {
          "text": "Non-Network Provider",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 130,
          "end": 150
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospital, Day Care Centre",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 161,
          "end": 186
        },
        {
          "text": "Network",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 229,
          "end": 236
        },
        {
          "text": "34",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 238,
          "end": 240
        },
        {
          "text": "35",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 404,
          "end": 406
        },
        {
          "text": "OPD",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 408,
          "end": 411
        },
        {
          "text": "OPD",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 424,
          "end": 427
        },
        {
          "text": "/ Hospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 489,
          "end": 499
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 627,
          "end": 634
        },
        {
          "text": "36",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 689,
          "end": 691
        },
        {
          "text": "one",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 923,
          "end": 926
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.0
    },
    {
      "text": "under family cover) to transfer the credit gained for pre-existing conditions and time-bound exclusions from\none insurer to another.\nUIN- BAJHLIP23020V012223 Global Health Care/ Policy Wordings/Page 4\nBajaj Allianz General Insurance Co. Ltd.\nBajaj Allianz House, Airport Road, Yerawada, Pune - 411 006. Reg. No.: 113\nFor more details, log on to: www.bajajallianz.com | E-mail: bagichelp@bajajallianz.co.in or\nCall at: Sales - 1800 209 0144 / Service - 1800 209 5858 (Toll Free No.)\nIssuing Office: GLOBAL HEALTH CARE\n37. Pre-Existing Disease:-\nPre-Existing Disease means any condition, ailment or Injury or disease\na. That is/are diagnosed by a physician within 48 months prior to the effective date of the Policy issued by the\ninsurer\nor\nb. For which medical advice or treatment was recommended by, or received from, a physician within 48 months\nprior to the effective date of the Policy or its reinstatement.\n38. Pre-Hospitalization Medical Expenses:-",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "one",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 109,
          "end": 112
        },
        {
          "text": "Global Health Care/",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 158,
          "end": 177
        },
        {
          "text": "4",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 199,
          "end": 200
        },
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz General Insurance Co. Ltd.",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 201,
          "end": 241
        },
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz House",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 242,
          "end": 261
        },
        {
          "text": "Airport Road",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 263,
          "end": 275
        },
        {
          "text": "Yerawada",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 277,
          "end": 285
        },
        {
          "text": "Pune",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 287,
          "end": 291
        },
        {
          "text": "113",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 313,
          "end": 316
        },
        {
          "text": "bagichelp@bajajallianz.co.in",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 377,
          "end": 405
        },
        {
          "text": "Sales - 1800",
          "type": "EVENT",
          "start": 418,
          "end": 430
        },
        {
          "text": "37",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 517,
          "end": 519
        },
        {
          "text": "48 months",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 662,
          "end": 671
        },
        {
          "text": "Policy",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 707,
          "end": 713
        },
        {
          "text": "48 months",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 837,
          "end": 846
        },
        {
          "text": "Policy",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 882,
          "end": 888
        },
        {
          "text": "38",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 911,
          "end": 913
        },
        {
          "text": "Pre-Hospitalization Medical Expenses:-",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 915,
          "end": 953
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "prior to the effective date of the Policy or its reinstatement.\n38. Pre-Hospitalization Medical Expenses:-\nPre-Hospitalization Medical Expenses means medical expenses incurred during pre-defined number of days\npreceding the Hospitalization of the Insured, provided that:\ni. Such Medical Expenses are incurred for the same condition for which the Insured’s Hospitalization was\nrequired, and\nii. The In-patient Hospitalization claim for such Hospitalization is admissible by the Insurance Company.\n39. Post-Hospitalization Medical Expenses:-\nPost-Hospitalization Medical Expenses means medical expenses incurred during pre-defined number of days\nimmediately after the Insured is discharged from the Hospital provided that:\ni. Such Medical Expenses are for the same condition for which the Insured’s Hospitalization was required, and\nii. The Inpatient Hospitalization claim for such Hospitalization is admissible by the Insurance Company.\n40. Reasonable and Customary Charges:-",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Policy",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 35,
          "end": 41
        },
        {
          "text": "38",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 64,
          "end": 66
        },
        {
          "text": "Pre-Hospitalization Medical Expenses:-",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 68,
          "end": 106
        },
        {
          "text": "Pre-Hospitalization Medical Expenses means medical",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 107,
          "end": 157
        },
        {
          "text": "days",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 205,
          "end": 209
        },
        {
          "text": "the Hospitalization of the Insured",
          "type": "EVENT",
          "start": 220,
          "end": 254
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospitalization",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 409,
          "end": 424
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospitalization",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 440,
          "end": 455
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insurance Company",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 473,
          "end": 494
        },
        {
          "text": "39",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 496,
          "end": 498
        },
        {
          "text": "Post-Hospitalization Medical Expenses:-\n",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 500,
          "end": 540
        },
        {
          "text": "Post-Hospitalization Medical Expenses means medical",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 540,
          "end": 591
        },
        {
          "text": "days",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 639,
          "end": 643
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 666,
          "end": 673
        },
        {
          "text": "The Inpatient Hospitalization",
          "type": "WORK_OF_ART",
          "start": 835,
          "end": 864
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospitalization",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 880,
          "end": 895
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insurance Company",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 913,
          "end": 934
        },
        {
          "text": "40",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 936,
          "end": 938
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "ii. The Inpatient Hospitalization claim for such Hospitalization is admissible by the Insurance Company.\n40. Reasonable and Customary Charges:-\nReasonable and Customary Charges means the charges for services or supplies, which are the standard charges\nfor the specific provider and consistent with the prevailing charges in the geographical area for identical or similar\nservices, taking into account the nature of the Illness / Injury involved.\n41. Qualified Nurse:-\nQualified nurse means a person who holds a valid registration from the Nursing Council of India or the Nursing\nCouncil of any state in India.\n42. Renewal:-\nRenewal means the terms on which the contract of insurance can be renewed on mutual consent with a provision\nof grace period for treating the renewal continuous for the purpose of gaining credit for pre-existing diseases,\ntime-bound exclusions and for all waiting periods.\n43. Room Rent:-",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "The Inpatient Hospitalization",
          "type": "WORK_OF_ART",
          "start": 4,
          "end": 33
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospitalization",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 49,
          "end": 64
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insurance Company",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 82,
          "end": 103
        },
        {
          "text": "40",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 105,
          "end": 107
        },
        {
          "text": "the Illness / Injury",
          "type": "EVENT",
          "start": 415,
          "end": 435
        },
        {
          "text": "41",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 446,
          "end": 448
        },
        {
          "text": "the Nursing Council of India",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 535,
          "end": 563
        },
        {
          "text": "the Nursing\nCouncil",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 567,
          "end": 586
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 603,
          "end": 608
        },
        {
          "text": "42",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 610,
          "end": 612
        },
        {
          "text": "43",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 897,
          "end": 899
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "time-bound exclusions and for all waiting periods.\n43. Room Rent:-\nRoom Rent means the amount charged by a Hospital towards Room and Boarding expenses and shall include\nthe associated medical expenses.\n44. Surgery or Surgical Procedure:-\nSurgery or Surgical Procedure means manual and / or operative procedure (s) required for treatment of an Illness\nor Injury, correction of deformities and defects, diagnosis and cure of diseases, relief from suffering and\nprolongation of life, performed in a Hospital or Day Care Centre by a Medical Practitioner.\n45. Unproven/Experimental Treatment:-\nUnproven/Experimental treatment means the treatment, including drug experimental therapy, which is not based\non established medical practice in India, is treatment experimental or unproven.",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "43",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 51,
          "end": 53
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 202,
          "end": 204
        },
        {
          "text": "Injury",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 354,
          "end": 360
        },
        {
          "text": "45",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 551,
          "end": 553
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 733,
          "end": 738
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "SECTION B) DEFINITIONS - SPECIFIC DEFINITIONS",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [],
      "entities": [],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "1. Accidental shall be construed as per definition of Accident in Standard Definitions.",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "1",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 1
        },
        {
          "text": "Accident",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 54,
          "end": 62
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.0
    },
    {
      "text": "2. Act of Terrorism:-\nMeans an act or thing by any person or group(s) of persons, whether acting alone or on behalf of or in connection\nwith or in connivance with or at the instance or instigation of any person or group(s) or organisation(s) or\nassociations(s), who are committed or proclaimed to be committed for political, religious or ideological purposes,\nwhether such person or group(s) of persons or organisation(s) or association(s) are or are not banned any law, in\nsuch a manner or with intent to threaten the unity, integrity, security or sovereignty of India or to strike terror in\nthe people or any section of the people by using bombs, dynamite or other explosive substances or inflammable\nsubstances or firearms or other lethal weapons or poisons or noxious gases or other chemicals or by any other\nsubstances (whether biological or otherwise) of a hazardous nature or by any other means whatsoever, with\nUIN- BAJHLIP23020V012223 Global Health Care/ Policy Wordings/Page 5",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 1
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 564,
          "end": 569
        },
        {
          "text": "5",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 985,
          "end": 986
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "UIN- BAJHLIP23020V012223 Global Health Care/ Policy Wordings/Page 5\nBajaj Allianz General Insurance Co. Ltd.\nBajaj Allianz House, Airport Road, Yerawada, Pune - 411 006. Reg. No.: 113\nFor more details, log on to: www.bajajallianz.com | E-mail: bagichelp@bajajallianz.co.in or\nCall at: Sales - 1800 209 0144 / Service - 1800 209 5858 (Toll Free No.)\nIssuing Office: GLOBAL HEALTH CARE\nintend to cause, or likely to cause, death or, or injuries to any person or persons or loss of, or damage to, or\ndestruction of, property or disruption of any supplies or services essential to the life of the community or causes\ndamage or destruction of any property or equipment used or intended to be used for the defence of India or in\nconnection with any other purposes of the Government of India, any State Government or an of their agencies, or\ndetains any person and threatens to kill or injure such person in order to compel the Government or any other",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Global Health Care/",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 25,
          "end": 44
        },
        {
          "text": "5",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 66,
          "end": 67
        },
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz General Insurance Co. Ltd.",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 68,
          "end": 108
        },
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz House",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 109,
          "end": 128
        },
        {
          "text": "Airport Road",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 130,
          "end": 142
        },
        {
          "text": "Yerawada",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 144,
          "end": 152
        },
        {
          "text": "Pune",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 154,
          "end": 158
        },
        {
          "text": "113",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 180,
          "end": 183
        },
        {
          "text": "bagichelp@bajajallianz.co.in",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 244,
          "end": 272
        },
        {
          "text": "Sales - 1800",
          "type": "EVENT",
          "start": 285,
          "end": 297
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 711,
          "end": 716
        },
        {
          "text": "the Government of India",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 761,
          "end": 784
        },
        {
          "text": "State Government",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 790,
          "end": 806
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "detains any person and threatens to kill or injure such person in order to compel the Government or any other\nperson to do or abstain from doing any act. Provided further that for the above acts appropriate criminal\nprosecution has been initiated by police and charge sheet has been filed in competent court of criminal\njurisdiction, either under special law or under general law.",
      "type": "GENERAL",
      "subtypes": [],
      "entities": [],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "3. Bajaj Allianz Network Hospitals / Network Hospitals/Network Providers:-\nBajaj Allianz Network Hospitals / Network Hospitals means the Hospitals which have been empanelled by the\nInsurer as per the latest version of the list of Hospitals maintained by the Insurer, which is available to You on\nrequest. For updated list please visit Our website.\n4. Bajaj Allianz Diagnostic Centre:-\nBajaj Allianz Diagnostic Centre means the diagnostic centers which have been empanelled by Us as per the latest\nversion of the schedule of diagnostic centers maintained by Us, which is available to You on request.\n5. Alternate/Complementary treatment:-\nComplementary treatment refers to therapeutic and diagnostic treatment that exists outside of traditional Western\nmedicine viz. chiropractic treatment, osteopathy, Chinese herbal medicine, homeopathy, acupuncture and\npodiatry as practised by approved therapists.\n6. Dental prescription drugs outside India:-",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "3",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 1
        },
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz Network Hospitals / Network Hospitals/Network",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 3,
          "end": 62
        },
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz Network Hospitals / Network Hospitals",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 75,
          "end": 126
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospitals",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 137,
          "end": 146
        },
        {
          "text": "the\nInsurer",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 177,
          "end": 188
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospitals",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 230,
          "end": 239
        },
        {
          "text": "Insurer",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 258,
          "end": 265
        },
        {
          "text": "4",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 348,
          "end": 349
        },
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz Diagnostic",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 351,
          "end": 375
        },
        {
          "text": "Centre:-\nBajaj Allianz Diagnostic Centre",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 376,
          "end": 416
        },
        {
          "text": "Us",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 476,
          "end": 478
        },
        {
          "text": "Us",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 557,
          "end": 559
        },
        {
          "text": "5",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 599,
          "end": 600
        },
        {
          "text": "Chinese",
          "type": "NORP",
          "start": 802,
          "end": 809
        },
        {
          "text": "6",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 901,
          "end": 902
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "podiatry as practised by approved therapists.\n6. Dental prescription drugs outside India:-\nDental prescription drugs outside India refers to those prescribed by a dentist for the treatment of dental\ninflammation or infection. The prescription drugs must be proven to be effective for the condition and recognized\nby the pharmaceutical regulator in a given country. They do not include mouthwashes, fluoride products,\nantiseptic gels and toothpastes.\n7. Dental prostheses outside India:-\nDental prostheses outside India includes crowns, inlays, onlays, adhesive reconstructions/restorations, bridges,\ndentures and implants as well as all necessary and ancillary treatment required\n8. Dental surgery outside India:-\nDental surgery outside India includes the surgical extraction of teeth, as well as other tooth-related surgical\nprocedures such as apicoectomy and dental prescription drugs. All investigative procedures that establish the",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "6",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 46,
          "end": 47
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 125,
          "end": 130
        },
        {
          "text": "7",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 450,
          "end": 451
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 513,
          "end": 518
        },
        {
          "text": "8",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 680,
          "end": 681
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 737,
          "end": 742
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.0
    },
    {
      "text": "procedures such as apicoectomy and dental prescription drugs. All investigative procedures that establish the\nneed for dental surgery such as laboratory tests, X-rays, CT scans and MRI(s) are included under this benefit.\nDental surgery does not cover surgical treatment that relates to dental implants.\n9. Dental treatment outside India:-\nDental treatment outside India includes an annual check-up, simple fillings related to cavities or decay, root canal\ntreatment and dental prescription drugs.\n10. Dependent:-\nDependent means a family member who is Your spouse, children and parents/parents-in-law.\n11. Dependent child:-\nA child is considered a dependent for insurance purposes up to the day before his/her 25th birthday. If enrolled in\nfull time education a child is considered as dependent up to the day before his/her 30th birthday provided he is\nfinancially dependent on the proposer.\n12. Diagnostic tests:-",
      "type": "LIMITATION",
      "subtypes": [
        "LIMITATION",
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION",
        "COVERAGE"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "CT",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 168,
          "end": 170
        },
        {
          "text": "MRI(s",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 181,
          "end": 186
        },
        {
          "text": "9",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 303,
          "end": 304
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 364,
          "end": 369
        },
        {
          "text": "annual",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 382,
          "end": 388
        },
        {
          "text": "10",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 497,
          "end": 499
        },
        {
          "text": "Dependent:-\nDependent",
          "type": "WORK_OF_ART",
          "start": 501,
          "end": 522
        },
        {
          "text": "11",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 602,
          "end": 604
        },
        {
          "text": "25th",
          "type": "ORDINAL",
          "start": 710,
          "end": 714
        },
        {
          "text": "30th",
          "type": "ORDINAL",
          "start": 824,
          "end": 828
        },
        {
          "text": "12",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 892,
          "end": 894
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.0
    },
    {
      "text": "financially dependent on the proposer.\n12. Diagnostic tests:-\nDiagnostic tests refers to investigations such as x-rays or blood tests, undertaken to determine the cause of the\npresented symptoms.\n13. Emergency and Emergency Treatment\nEmergency Treatment shall be accordingly taken/interpreted as per definition of Emergency Care read with this\ndefinition. Provided however only treatment commencing within 24 hours of the Emergency event will be covered.\n14. Emergency Inpatient Dental Treatment arising from an Accident:-\nEmergency Inpatient Dental Treatment arising from an Accident refers to acute Emergency Dental Treatment that\nis due to a serious Accident and requires admission to Hospital. The treatment must take place within 24 hours of\nUIN- BAJHLIP23020V012223 Global Health Care/ Policy Wordings/Page 6\nBajaj Allianz General Insurance Co. Ltd.\nBajaj Allianz House, Airport Road, Yerawada, Pune - 411 006. Reg. No.: 113",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION",
        "COVERAGE"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "12",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 39,
          "end": 41
        },
        {
          "text": "Diagnostic",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 62,
          "end": 72
        },
        {
          "text": "13",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 196,
          "end": 198
        },
        {
          "text": "24 hours",
          "type": "TIME",
          "start": 406,
          "end": 414
        },
        {
          "text": "14",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 455,
          "end": 457
        },
        {
          "text": "Accident",
          "type": "LOC",
          "start": 576,
          "end": 584
        },
        {
          "text": "Emergency Dental Treatment",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 601,
          "end": 627
        },
        {
          "text": "Accident",
          "type": "LOC",
          "start": 653,
          "end": 661
        },
        {
          "text": "24 hours",
          "type": "TIME",
          "start": 735,
          "end": 743
        },
        {
          "text": "6",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 813,
          "end": 814
        },
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz General Insurance Co. Ltd.",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 815,
          "end": 855
        },
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz House",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 856,
          "end": 875
        },
        {
          "text": "Airport Road",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 877,
          "end": 889
        },
        {
          "text": "Yerawada",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 891,
          "end": 899
        },
        {
          "text": "Pune",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 901,
          "end": 905
        },
        {
          "text": "113",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 927,
          "end": 930
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.0
    },
    {
      "text": "Bajaj Allianz General Insurance Co. Ltd.\nBajaj Allianz House, Airport Road, Yerawada, Pune - 411 006. Reg. No.: 113\nFor more details, log on to: www.bajajallianz.com | E-mail: bagichelp@bajajallianz.co.in or\nCall at: Sales - 1800 209 0144 / Service - 1800 209 5858 (Toll Free No.)\nIssuing Office: GLOBAL HEALTH CARE\nthe Emergency event. Cover does not extend to follow-up Dental Treatment, dental surgery, dental prostheses,\northodontics or periodontics.\n15. Emergency Treatment outside area of cover:-\nEmergency treatment outside area of cover is treatment for medical emergencies which occur during business or\nholiday trips outside Your area of cover. Cover is provided for up to six weeks per trip within the maximum benefit\namount. It includes treatment required due to an Accident or the sudden beginning or worsening of a severe\nIllness which presents an immediate threat to Your health. Treatment by a Doctor must start within 24 hours of",
      "type": "LIMITATION",
      "subtypes": [
        "CONDITION",
        "LIMITATION",
        "COVERAGE"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz General Insurance Co. Ltd.",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 40
        },
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz House",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 41,
          "end": 60
        },
        {
          "text": "Airport Road",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 62,
          "end": 74
        },
        {
          "text": "Yerawada",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 76,
          "end": 84
        },
        {
          "text": "Pune",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 86,
          "end": 90
        },
        {
          "text": "113",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 112,
          "end": 115
        },
        {
          "text": "bagichelp@bajajallianz.co.in",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 176,
          "end": 204
        },
        {
          "text": "Sales - 1800",
          "type": "EVENT",
          "start": 217,
          "end": 229
        },
        {
          "text": "Dental Treatment",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 372,
          "end": 388
        },
        {
          "text": "15",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 455,
          "end": 457
        },
        {
          "text": "up to six weeks",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 677,
          "end": 692
        },
        {
          "text": "Accident",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 778,
          "end": 786
        },
        {
          "text": "24 hours",
          "type": "TIME",
          "start": 935,
          "end": 943
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "Illness which presents an immediate threat to Your health. Treatment by a Doctor must start within 24 hours of\nthe Emergency event. Cover is not provided for curative or follow-up non-Emergency treatment, even if You are\ndeemed unable to travel to a country within Your geographical area of cover. Nor does it extend to charges\nrelating to maternity, pregnancy, childbirth or any complications of pregnancy or childbirth. You must tell Us if You\nare going to be outside Your area of cover for more than six weeks.\n16. Endorsement:-\nEndorsement means any writing on a Policy Schedule or Policy, in addition to its normal Policy Schedule/Policy\nwording/Standard Terms and Conditions which supplements or modifies its Policy Schedule/Policy\nWording/Standard Terms and Conditions. It may be added when Policy is prepared, or subsequently. Provided\nhowever any Service Level Agreement [SLA] or Agreement/MOU laying down various service levels shall not be\ntreated as Endorsement.\n17. Family history:-",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "24 hours",
          "type": "TIME",
          "start": 99,
          "end": 107
        },
        {
          "text": "Us",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 436,
          "end": 438
        },
        {
          "text": "more than six weeks",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 493,
          "end": 512
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 514,
          "end": 516
        },
        {
          "text": "Service Level Agreement",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 856,
          "end": 879
        },
        {
          "text": "SLA",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 881,
          "end": 884
        },
        {
          "text": "17",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 975,
          "end": 977
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.6666666666666666
    },
    {
      "text": "treated as Endorsement.\n17. Family history:-\nFamily history exists where a parent, grandparent, sibling, child, aunt or uncle has been previously diagnosed with\nthe medical condition in question.\n18. Home Country:-\nHome country is a country for which You hold a current passport or which is Your principal country of residence.\n19. Hospital (for International Cover):-\nHospital for international practice is any establishment which is licensed as a medical or surgical Hospital in the\ncountry where it operates and where the patient is permanently supervised by a Doctor.\nThe following are not considered Hospitals:\n“rest and nursing homes, spas, cure-centres and health resorts.”\n20. Inpatient:- shall be construed as per Standard Definition of Inpatient Care.\n21. Inpatient cash benefit:-\nIn-patient cash benefit is payable when You receive Inpatient treatment free of charge for a medical condition that",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "CONDITION",
        "COVERAGE"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "17",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 24,
          "end": 26
        },
        {
          "text": "18",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 196,
          "end": 198
        },
        {
          "text": "19",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 328,
          "end": 330
        },
        {
          "text": "International Cover):-\nHospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 346,
          "end": 377
        },
        {
          "text": "surgical Hospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 460,
          "end": 477
        },
        {
          "text": "20",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 681,
          "end": 683
        },
        {
          "text": "21",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 762,
          "end": 764
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "21. Inpatient cash benefit:-\nIn-patient cash benefit is payable when You receive Inpatient treatment free of charge for a medical condition that\nis covered by Us. Cover is limited to the amount and maximum number of nights specified in the Table of Benefits\nand is payable after You are discharged from Hospital.\n20. Limit of Indemnity:-\nLimit of Indemnity represents Our maximum liability to make payment for each and every claim per person and\ncollectively for all persons mentioned in the Policy Schedule during the Policy Period and in the aggregate for the\nperson(s) named in the Policy Schedule during the Policy Period, and means the amount stated in the Policy\nSchedule against each Cover.\n21. Living donor medical costs:-\nLiving donor medical costs refer to the expenses We pay up to the limits specified in the Policy Schedule, towards\norgan donor’s treatment for harvesting of the donated organ, provided that,",
      "type": "LIMITATION",
      "subtypes": [
        "LIMITATION",
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION",
        "COVERAGE"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "21",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 2
        },
        {
          "text": "Us",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 159,
          "end": 161
        },
        {
          "text": "nights",
          "type": "TIME",
          "start": 216,
          "end": 222
        },
        {
          "text": "the Table of Benefits",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 236,
          "end": 257
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 303,
          "end": 311
        },
        {
          "text": "20",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 313,
          "end": 315
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Period",
          "type": "LAW",
          "start": 515,
          "end": 532
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Schedule",
          "type": "LAW",
          "start": 581,
          "end": 600
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Period",
          "type": "EVENT",
          "start": 608,
          "end": 625
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy\nSchedule",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 658,
          "end": 677
        },
        {
          "text": "Cover",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 691,
          "end": 696
        },
        {
          "text": "21",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 698,
          "end": 700
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Schedule",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 817,
          "end": 836
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.6666666666666666
    },
    {
      "text": "organ donor’s treatment for harvesting of the donated organ, provided that,\n The organ donor is any person whose organ has been made available in accordance and in compliance with\nthe local regulation and the organ donated is for the use of the Insured, and\n We have accepted an Inpatient Hospitalization claim for the Insured under In-patient Hospitalization treatment\nfor organ transplant.\n22. Local (Road) ambulance:-\nLocal (Road) ambulance is ambulance transport that is required for an Emergency or out of medical necessity, to\nthe nearest available and appropriate Hospital or licensed medical facility.\n23. Medical Consumable:-\nMedical consumable and equipment includes syringes, needles, sutures, staples, packaging, tubing,\ncatheters, medical gloves, gowns, masks, adhesives and sealants for wound dressing and a whole host of other\ndevices and tools used with a Hospital or surgical environment\nUIN- BAJHLIP23020V012223 Global Health Care/ Policy Wordings/Page 7",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 76,
          "end": 77
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 246,
          "end": 253
        },
        {
          "text": "",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 259,
          "end": 260
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 321,
          "end": 328
        },
        {
          "text": "22",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 394,
          "end": 396
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 573,
          "end": 581
        },
        {
          "text": "23",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 612,
          "end": 614
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 874,
          "end": 882
        },
        {
          "text": "Global Health Care/",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 932,
          "end": 951
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "devices and tools used with a Hospital or surgical environment\nUIN- BAJHLIP23020V012223 Global Health Care/ Policy Wordings/Page 7\nBajaj Allianz General Insurance Co. Ltd.\nBajaj Allianz House, Airport Road, Yerawada, Pune - 411 006. Reg. No.: 113\nFor more details, log on to: www.bajajallianz.com | E-mail: bagichelp@bajajallianz.co.in or\nCall at: Sales - 1800 209 0144 / Service - 1800 209 5858 (Toll Free No.)\nIssuing Office: GLOBAL HEALTH CARE\n24. Medical Practitioners/Doctor (for International Cover):-\nMedical Practitioners/Doctor for international practice are Doctors who are licensed to practise medicine under\nthe law of the country in which Medically Necessary Treatment is given and where they are practising within the\nlimits of their licence.\n25. Medical Practitioner fees:-\nMedical Practitioner fees refers to non-surgical treatment performed or administered by a Medical Practitioner.\n26. Medical underwriting:-",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Hospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 30,
          "end": 38
        },
        {
          "text": "Global Health Care/",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 88,
          "end": 107
        },
        {
          "text": "7",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 129,
          "end": 130
        },
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz General Insurance Co. Ltd.",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 131,
          "end": 171
        },
        {
          "text": "Bajaj Allianz House",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 172,
          "end": 191
        },
        {
          "text": "Airport Road",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 193,
          "end": 205
        },
        {
          "text": "Yerawada",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 207,
          "end": 215
        },
        {
          "text": "Pune",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 217,
          "end": 221
        },
        {
          "text": "113",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 243,
          "end": 246
        },
        {
          "text": "bagichelp@bajajallianz.co.in",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 307,
          "end": 335
        },
        {
          "text": "Sales - 1800",
          "type": "EVENT",
          "start": 348,
          "end": 360
        },
        {
          "text": "24",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 447,
          "end": 449
        },
        {
          "text": "International Cover):-\nMedical Practitioners/Doctor",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 485,
          "end": 536
        },
        {
          "text": "25",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 757,
          "end": 759
        },
        {
          "text": "26",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 901,
          "end": 903
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.0
    },
    {
      "text": "Medical Practitioner fees refers to non-surgical treatment performed or administered by a Medical Practitioner.\n26. Medical underwriting:-\nMedical underwriting is the assessment of insurance risk based on information that You give Us when applying for\ncover. Our underwriting team uses this information to decide the terms of Our offer.\n27. \"Mental Illness\" means a substantial disorder of thinking, mood, perception, orientation or memory that grossly\nimpairs judgment, behaviour, capacity to recognise reality or ability to meet the ordinary demands of life, but does\nnot include mental retardation which is a condition of arrested or incomplete development of mind of a person,\nspecially characterised by sub normality of intelligence;\n28. Named Insured/ Insured/Insured Person:\nInsured means the persons, or his Family Members, named in the Schedule provided that an Insured or his\nFamily Members has attained the age of 3 months and is not older than 65 years of age at the commencement of",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "26",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 112,
          "end": 114
        },
        {
          "text": "Us",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 231,
          "end": 233
        },
        {
          "text": "27",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 337,
          "end": 339
        },
        {
          "text": "28",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 739,
          "end": 741
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured/ Insured/Insured Person:\nInsured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 749,
          "end": 789
        },
        {
          "text": "Family",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 816,
          "end": 822
        },
        {
          "text": "Schedule",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 845,
          "end": 853
        },
        {
          "text": "the age of 3 months",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 914,
          "end": 933
        },
        {
          "text": "older than 65 years of age",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 945,
          "end": 971
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 1.0
    },
    {
      "text": "Family Members has attained the age of 3 months and is not older than 65 years of age at the commencement of\nfirst Global Health Care Policy.\n29. Network shall be construed as per the Standard Definition of Network Provider.\n30. Obesity:-\nObesity means abnormal or excessive fat accumulation that may impair health. Obesity is measured in Body\nMass Index.\nBody mass index (BMI) is a simple index of weight-for-height that is commonly used to classify overweight and\nobesity in adults. It is defined as a person's weight in kilograms divided by the square of his height in meters\n(kg/m2).\nThe WHO definition is:\n BMI greater than or equal to 25 is overweight\n BMI greater than or equal to 30 is obesity\n31. Oral and maxillofacial surgical procedures outside India:-\nOral and maxillofacial surgical procedures outside India refers to surgical treatment on the mouth, jaws, face or\nneck performed in a Hospital by an oral and maxillofacial surgeon for: oral pathology, temporomandibular joint",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "the age of 3 months",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 28,
          "end": 47
        },
        {
          "text": "older than 65 years of age",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 59,
          "end": 85
        },
        {
          "text": "first",
          "type": "ORDINAL",
          "start": 109,
          "end": 114
        },
        {
          "text": "29",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 142,
          "end": 144
        },
        {
          "text": "30",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 225,
          "end": 227
        },
        {
          "text": "(kg/m2",
          "type": "QUANTITY",
          "start": 579,
          "end": 585
        },
        {
          "text": "",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 611,
          "end": 612
        },
        {
          "text": "25",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 642,
          "end": 644
        },
        {
          "text": "",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 659,
          "end": 660
        },
        {
          "text": "30",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 690,
          "end": 692
        },
        {
          "text": "31",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 704,
          "end": 706
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 818,
          "end": 823
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "neck performed in a Hospital by an oral and maxillofacial surgeon for: oral pathology, temporomandibular joint\ndisorders, facial bone fractures, congenital jaw deformities, salivary gland diseases and tumours.\nUnless You hold an International Dental Plan, We do not cover the following procedures even if they are\nperformed by an oral and maxillofacial surgeon:\n Surgical removal of impacted teeth\n Surgical removal of cysts\n Orthognathic surgeries for the correction of malocclusion.\n32. Organ transplant:-\nOrgan transplant refers to the following organ or tissue transplants: heart, heart/valve, heart/lung, liver, pancreas,\npancreas/kidney, kidney, bone marrow, parathyroid, muscular/skeletal and cornea.\n33. Periodontics (for international practice):-\nPeriodontics refers to Dental Treatment related to gum disease.\n34. Podiatry\nPodiatry refers to Medically Necessary Treatment carried out by a State Registered podiatrist.\n35. Policy or Contract/ Global Health Care Policy:-",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 362,
          "end": 363
        },
        {
          "text": "",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 399,
          "end": 400
        },
        {
          "text": "",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 427,
          "end": 428
        },
        {
          "text": "32",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 488,
          "end": 490
        },
        {
          "text": "33",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 711,
          "end": 713
        },
        {
          "text": "Dental Treatment",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 782,
          "end": 798
        },
        {
          "text": "34",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 823,
          "end": 825
        },
        {
          "text": "Podiatry\nPodiatry",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 827,
          "end": 844
        },
        {
          "text": "State",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 902,
          "end": 907
        },
        {
          "text": "35",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 931,
          "end": 933
        },
        {
          "text": "Contract/ Global Health Care Policy:-",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 945,
          "end": 982
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "Podiatry refers to Medically Necessary Treatment carried out by a State Registered podiatrist.\n35. Policy or Contract/ Global Health Care Policy:-\nPolicy or Contract means the Proposal, the Policy Schedule, along with these Terms and Conditions issued to the\nInsured and any annexures and/or Endorsements attaching to and / or forming part thereof either at the\ncommencement of Policy Period or during the Policy Period.\nUIN- BAJHLIP23020V012223 Global Health Care/ Policy Wordings/Page 8\nBajaj Allianz General Insurance Co. Ltd.\nBajaj Allianz House, Airport Road, Yerawada, Pune - 411 006. Reg. No.: 113\nFor more details, log on to: www.bajajallianz.com | E-mail: bagichelp@bajajallianz.co.in or\nCall at: Sales - 1800 209 0144 / Service - 1800 209 5858 (Toll Free No.)\nIssuing Office: GLOBAL HEALTH CARE\n36. Policy Schedule or Schedule:-\nPolicy Schedule means the Policy Schedule and any annexure or Endorsements to it, if any, as issued by the\nCompany, which forms part of Policy.",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "State",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 66,
          "end": 71
        },
        {
          "text": "35",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 95,
          "end": 97
        },
        {
          "text": "Contract/ Global Health Care Policy:-\nPolicy or",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 109,
          "end": 156
        },
        {
          "text": "Proposal",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 176,
          "end": 184
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Schedule",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 186,
          "end": 205
        },
        {
          "text": "Policy Period",
          "type": "WORK_OF_ART",
          "start": 378,
