{
  "metadata": {
    "source_file": "CHOTGDP23004V012223.pdf",
    "policy_number": "etc",
    "effective_date": null,
    "coverage_types": [
      "health",
      "accident",
      "property",
      "liability",
      "auto"
    ],
    "file_info": {
      "path": "G:\\project\\life_insurence_query\\file_inputs\\CHOTGDP23004V012223.pdf",
      "last_modified": "2025-07-25 16:00:57.861813"
    }
  },
  "clauses": [
    {
      "text": "CHOLAMANDALAM MS GENERAL INSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED\nRegistered Office: 2nd Floor, “DARE House”, 2, N.S.C. Bose Road, Chennai – 600 001.\nToll free: 1800 208 9100, T: +91 (0) 44 4044 5400, F: +91 (0) 44 4044 5550\nE: customercare@cholams.murugappa.com; website: www.cholainsurance.com\nIRDA Regn. No.123; PAN AABCC6633K CIN U66030TN2001PLC047977\nGROUP DOMESTIC TRAVEL INSURANCE\nCHOTGDP23004V012223\nPolicy Wordings\nGROUP DOMESTIC TRAVEL INSURANCE\nPage 1 of 101\nCHOLAMANDALAM MS GENERAL INSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED\nRegistered Office: 2nd Floor, “DARE House”, 2, N.S.C. Bose Road, Chennai – 600 001.\nToll free: 1800 208 9100, T: +91 (0) 44 4044 5400, F: +91 (0) 44 4044 5550\nE: customercare@cholams.murugappa.com; website: www.cholainsurance.com\nIRDA Regn. No.123; PAN AABCC6633K CIN U66030TN2001PLC047977\nGROUP DOMESTIC TRAVEL INSURANCE\nCHOTGDP23004V012223\nPolicy Wordings\nWe issue this Group insurance policy to the Proposer based on the information provided by the Proposer in the",
      "type": "LIMITATION",
      "subtypes": [],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "CHOLAMANDALAM MS",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 16
        },
        {
          "text": "GENERAL INSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED\nRegistered Office",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 17,
          "end": 68
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 95,
          "end": 96
        },
        {
          "text": "N.S.C. Bose Road",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 98,
          "end": 114
        },
        {
          "text": "Chennai",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 116,
          "end": 123
        },
        {
          "text": "600",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 126,
          "end": 129
        },
        {
          "text": "1800",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 146,
          "end": 150
        },
        {
          "text": "9100",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 155,
          "end": 159
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 169,
          "end": 170
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 172,
          "end": 174
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 194,
          "end": 195
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 197,
          "end": 199
        },
        {
          "text": "5550",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 205,
          "end": 209
        },
        {
          "text": "IRDA Regn",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 281,
          "end": 290
        },
        {
          "text": "PAN AABCC6633",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 300,
          "end": 313
        },
        {
          "text": "K CIN",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 313,
          "end": 318
        },
        {
          "text": "GROUP DOMESTIC TRAVEL INSURANCE",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 341,
          "end": 372
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 446,
          "end": 447
        },
        {
          "text": "101",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 451,
          "end": 454
        },
        {
          "text": "GENERAL INSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED\nRegistered Office",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 472,
          "end": 523
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 550,
          "end": 551
        },
        {
          "text": "N.S.C. Bose Road",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 553,
          "end": 569
        },
        {
          "text": "Chennai",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 571,
          "end": 578
        },
        {
          "text": "600",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 581,
          "end": 584
        },
        {
          "text": "1800",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 601,
          "end": 605
        },
        {
          "text": "9100",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 610,
          "end": 614
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 624,
          "end": 625
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 627,
          "end": 629
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 649,
          "end": 650
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 652,
          "end": 654
        },
        {
          "text": "5550",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 660,
          "end": 664
        },
        {
          "text": "IRDA Regn",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 736,
          "end": 745
        },
        {
          "text": "PAN AABCC6633",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 755,
          "end": 768
        },
        {
          "text": "K CIN",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 768,
          "end": 773
        },
        {
          "text": "GROUP DOMESTIC TRAVEL INSURANCE",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 796,
          "end": 827
        },
        {
          "text": "Group",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 878,
          "end": 883
        },
        {
          "text": "Proposer",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 908,
          "end": 916
        },
        {
          "text": "Proposer",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 958,
          "end": 966
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "CHOTGDP23004V012223\nPolicy Wordings\nWe issue this Group insurance policy to the Proposer based on the information provided by the Proposer in the\nproposal form and premium paid by the Proposer. This insurance is subject to the following terms and conditions.\nThe method of coverage and the Benefit Limits that has been opted is indicated in the Policy Schedule/Policy\nCertificate. The term You/Your/Insured/Insured Person in this document refers to the individual group members\nwho will be treated as Insured beneficiary and the term Proposer/Policy Holder/Group Manager/Group Organizer\nin this document refers to Person/ Organisation who has signed the proposal form and in whose name the policy is\nissued. Also the term Insurer/Us/Our/Company in this document refers to Cholamandalam MS General Insurance\nCompany Limited.\nMaster policy will be issued in the name of Group Manager and individual certificate may be issued to the\nbeneficiaries.",
      "type": "LIMITATION",
      "subtypes": [
        "COVERAGE",
        "DEFINITION",
        "LIMITATION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "CHOTGDP23004V012223\nPolicy Wordings",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 35
        },
        {
          "text": "Group",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 50,
          "end": 55
        },
        {
          "text": "Proposer",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 80,
          "end": 88
        },
        {
          "text": "Proposer",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 130,
          "end": 138
        },
        {
          "text": "Proposer",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 184,
          "end": 192
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Schedule/Policy\nCertificate",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 341,
          "end": 379
        },
        {
          "text": "Proposer/Policy Holder/Group",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 534,
          "end": 562
        },
        {
          "text": "Person/ Organisation",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 614,
          "end": 634
        },
        {
          "text": "Insurer/Us",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 722,
          "end": 732
        },
        {
          "text": "Cholamandalam MS General Insurance\nCompany Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 772,
          "end": 822
        },
        {
          "text": "Group",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 868,
          "end": 873
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "1. DEFINITIONS\nAny word or expression to which a specific meaning has been assigned in any part of this Policy or the Schedule/\nCertificate shall bear the same meaning wherever it appears in the Policy, including any subsequent\nendorsements to this Policy and the Policy Schedule/Certificate. Where the context permits, references to the\nsingular shall also include references to the plural, similarly references to the male gender shall also include\nreferences to the female gender, and vice versa in both cases.\nFor purposes of this Policy, the terms specified below shall have the meaning set forth:\nA) STANDARD DEFINITONS\nAccident / Accidental mean a sudden, unforeseen and involuntary event caused by external, visible and violent\nmeans.\nCashless facility means a facility extended by the Insurer to the insured where the payments, of the costs of treatment\nundergone by the insured in accordance with the policy terms and conditions, are directly made to the network provider",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "1",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 1
        },
        {
          "text": "Schedule/",
          "type": "LAW",
          "start": 118,
          "end": 127
        },
        {
          "text": "Policy",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 195,
          "end": 201
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Schedule/Certificate",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 260,
          "end": 291
        },
        {
          "text": "Policy",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 535,
          "end": 541
        },
        {
          "text": "Accident / Accidental",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 626,
          "end": 647
        },
        {
          "text": "Insurer",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 794,
          "end": 801
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "undergone by the insured in accordance with the policy terms and conditions, are directly made to the network provider\nby the Insurer to the extent pre-authorization is approved.\nCondition Precedent means a policy term or condition upon which the Insurer’s liability under the policy is\nconditional upon.\nCongenital Anomaly means a condition which is present since birth, which is abnormal with reference to form,\nstructure or position.\na. Internal Congenital Anomaly: Congenital anomaly which is not in the visible and accessible parts of the\nbody.\nb. External Congenital Anomaly: Congenital anomaly which is in the visible and accessible parts of the\nbody.\nDeductible means a cost-sharing requirement under this policy, that provides that the Insurer will not be liable\nfor a specified amount or percentage of claim amount and/or number of days and/or number of hours as\nspecified in the policy schedule/certificate of insurance which will apply before any benefits are payable by",
      "type": "COVERAGE",
      "subtypes": [
        "COVERAGE",
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Insurer",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 126,
          "end": 133
        },
        {
          "text": "Insurer",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 247,
          "end": 254
        },
        {
          "text": "b. External Congenital Anomaly",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 550,
          "end": 580
        },
        {
          "text": "Insurer",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 745,
          "end": 752
        },
        {
          "text": "days",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 842,
          "end": 846
        },
        {
          "text": "number of hours",
          "type": "TIME",
          "start": 854,
          "end": 869
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.6666666666666666
    },
    {
      "text": "specified in the policy schedule/certificate of insurance which will apply before any benefits are payable by\nthe Insurer. A deductible does not reduce the Sum Insured and is applicable per event up to the specified\nlimits mentioned.\nDisclosure to information norm means the Policy shall be void and all premium paid hereon shall be forfeited\nto the Company, in the event of misrepresentation, mis-description or non-disclosure of any material fact.\nHospital means any institution established for inpatient care and day care treatment of illness and/or injuries and\nwhich has been registered as a hospital with the local authorities under the Clinical Establishments (Registration and\nPage 2 of 101\nCHOLAMANDALAM MS GENERAL INSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED\nRegistered Office: 2nd Floor, “DARE House”, 2, N.S.C. Bose Road, Chennai – 600 001.\nToll free: 1800 208 9100, T: +91 (0) 44 4044 5400, F: +91 (0) 44 4044 5550\nE: customercare@cholams.murugappa.com; website: www.cholainsurance.com",
      "type": "LIMITATION",
      "subtypes": [
        "COVERAGE",
        "DEFINITION",
        "LIMITATION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Insurer",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 114,
          "end": 121
        },
        {
          "text": "Policy",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 275,
          "end": 281
        },
        {
          "text": "Company",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 350,
          "end": 357
        },
        {
          "text": "the Clinical Establishments (Registration",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 639,
          "end": 680
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 690,
          "end": 691
        },
        {
          "text": "101",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 695,
          "end": 698
        },
        {
          "text": "GENERAL INSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED\nRegistered Office",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 716,
          "end": 767
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 794,
          "end": 795
        },
        {
          "text": "N.S.C. Bose Road",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 797,
          "end": 813
        },
        {
          "text": "Chennai",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 815,
          "end": 822
        },
        {
          "text": "600",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 825,
          "end": 828
        },
        {
          "text": "1800",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 845,
          "end": 849
        },
        {
          "text": "9100",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 854,
          "end": 858
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 868,
          "end": 869
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 871,
          "end": 873
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 893,
          "end": 894
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 896,
          "end": 898
        },
        {
          "text": "5550",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 904,
          "end": 908
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "Toll free: 1800 208 9100, T: +91 (0) 44 4044 5400, F: +91 (0) 44 4044 5550\nE: customercare@cholams.murugappa.com; website: www.cholainsurance.com\nIRDA Regn. No.123; PAN AABCC6633K CIN U66030TN2001PLC047977\nGROUP DOMESTIC TRAVEL INSURANCE\nCHOTGDP23004V012223\nPolicy Wordings\nRegulation) Act 2010 or under the enactments specified under the Schedule of Section 56(1) of the said Act OR\ncomplies with all minimum criteria as under:",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "1800",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 11,
          "end": 15
        },
        {
          "text": "9100",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 20,
          "end": 24
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 34,
          "end": 35
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 37,
          "end": 39
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 59,
          "end": 60
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 62,
          "end": 64
        },
        {
          "text": "5550",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 70,
          "end": 74
        },
        {
          "text": "IRDA Regn",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 146,
          "end": 155
        },
        {
          "text": "PAN AABCC6633",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 165,
          "end": 178
        },
        {
          "text": "K CIN",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 178,
          "end": 183
        },
        {
          "text": "GROUP DOMESTIC TRAVEL INSURANCE",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 206,
          "end": 237
        },
        {
          "text": "2010",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 290,
          "end": 294
        },
        {
          "text": "the Schedule of Section 56(1",
          "type": "LAW",
          "start": 335,
          "end": 363
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "- has qualified nursing staff under its employment round the clock;\n- has at least 10 in-patient beds in towns having a population of less than 10,00,000 and at least 15\nin-patient beds in all other places;\n- has qualified medical practitioner(s) in charge round the clock;\n- has a fully equipped operation theatre of its own where surgical procedures are carried out;",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "at least 10",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 74,
          "end": 85
        },
        {
          "text": "less than 10,00,000",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 134,
          "end": 153
        },
        {
          "text": "at least 15",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 158,
          "end": 169
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "- maintains daily records of patients and makes these accessible to the insurance company’s\nauthorized personnel\nHospitalisation means admission in a Hospital for a minimum period of 24 consecutive ‘In-patient Care’ hours except\nfor specified procedures/ treatments, where such admission could be for a period of less than 24consecutive hours.\nIllness means a sickness or a disease or pathological condition leading to the impairment of normal physiological\nfunction and requires medical treatment.\na. Acute condition is a disease, illness or injury that is likely to respond quickly to treatment which aims to\nreturn the person to his or her state of health immediately before suffering the disease/illness/injury\nwhich leads to full recovery.\nb. Chronic condition is defined as a disease, illness, or injury that has one or more of the following\ncharacteristics:—it needs ongoing or long-term monitoring through consultations, examinations, check-",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "daily",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 12,
          "end": 17
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospitalisation",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 113,
          "end": 128
        },
        {
          "text": "24",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 183,
          "end": 185
        },
        {
          "text": "less than 24consecutive hours",
          "type": "TIME",
          "start": 313,
          "end": 342
        },
        {
          "text": "one",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 819,
          "end": 822
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "characteristics:—it needs ongoing or long-term monitoring through consultations, examinations, check-\nups, and / or tests—it needs ongoing or long-term control or relief of symptoms— it requires rehabilitation\nfor the patient or for the patient to be specially trained to cope with it—it continues indefinitely—it recurs\nor is likely to recur.\nInjury means accidental physical bodily harm excluding illness or disease, solely and directly caused by external,\nviolent and visible and evident means which is verified and certified by a Medical Practitioner.\nIn Patient Care means treatment for which the insured person has to stay in a hospital for more than 24 hours for a\ncovered event.\nMaternity Expenses means\na. medical treatment expenses traceable to childbirth (including complicated deliveries and\ncaesarean sections incurred during hospitalization)\nb. expenses towards lawful medical termination of pregnancy during the policy period",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "COVERAGE",
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "more than 24 hours",
          "type": "TIME",
          "start": 647,
          "end": 665
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "caesarean sections incurred during hospitalization)\nb. expenses towards lawful medical termination of pregnancy during the policy period\nMedical Advice means any consultation or advice from a Medical Practitioner including the issuance of any\nprescription or follow-up prescription\nMedical Expenses means those expenses that an Insured Person has necessarily and actually incurred for\nmedical treatment on account of Illness or Accident on the advice of a Medical Practitioner, as long as these\nare no more than would have been payable if the Insured Person had not been insured and no more than\nother hospitals or doctors in the same locality would have charged for the same medical treatment.\nMedical Practitioner means a person who holds a valid registration from the Medical Council or appropriate\nauthority of the country where Insured Person is availing emergency treatment outside India/ Country of",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "COVERAGE",
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Medical Advice",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 137,
          "end": 151
        },
        {
          "text": "Medical Practitioner",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 192,
          "end": 212
        },
        {
          "text": "an Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 325,
          "end": 342
        },
        {
          "text": "Accident",
          "type": "LOC",
          "start": 428,
          "end": 436
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 539,
          "end": 557
        },
        {
          "text": "the Medical Council",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 767,
          "end": 786
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 833,
          "end": 847
        },
        {
          "text": "India/ Country of",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 888,
          "end": 905
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "authority of the country where Insured Person is availing emergency treatment outside India/ Country of\norigin and is thereby entitled to practice medicine within its jurisdiction; and is acting within the scope and\njurisdiction of license. The term Medical Practitioner includes any qualified physician, specialist, or surgeon,\nand should not be an Immediate Family Member of the Insured Person or related to the Insured Person by\nway of blood, marriage, adoption, employment, or any pre-existing business relationship.\nMedically Necessary Treatment means any treatment, tests, medication, stay in Hospital or part of a stay\nin Hospital in relation to the Insured Person which:\ni. is required for the medical management of the Illness or Injury suffered by the Insured Person;\nPage 3 of 101\nCHOLAMANDALAM MS GENERAL INSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED\nRegistered Office: 2nd Floor, “DARE House”, 2, N.S.C. Bose Road, Chennai – 600 001.",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 31,
          "end": 45
        },
        {
          "text": "India/ Country",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 86,
          "end": 100
        },
        {
          "text": "Medical Practitioner",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 250,
          "end": 270
        },
        {
          "text": "Immediate Family",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 350,
          "end": 366
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 377,
          "end": 395
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 410,
          "end": 428
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 599,
          "end": 607
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 653,
          "end": 671
        },
        {
          "text": "the Illness or Injury",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 724,
          "end": 745
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 758,
          "end": 776
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 783,
          "end": 784
        },
        {
          "text": "101",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 788,
          "end": 791
        },
        {
          "text": "GENERAL INSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED\nRegistered Office",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 809,
          "end": 860
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 887,
          "end": 888
        },
        {
          "text": "N.S.C. Bose Road",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 890,
          "end": 906
        },
        {
          "text": "Chennai",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 908,
          "end": 915
        },
        {
          "text": "600",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 918,
          "end": 921
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "Page 3 of 101\nCHOLAMANDALAM MS GENERAL INSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED\nRegistered Office: 2nd Floor, “DARE House”, 2, N.S.C. Bose Road, Chennai – 600 001.\nToll free: 1800 208 9100, T: +91 (0) 44 4044 5400, F: +91 (0) 44 4044 5550\nE: customercare@cholams.murugappa.com; website: www.cholainsurance.com\nIRDA Regn. No.123; PAN AABCC6633K CIN U66030TN2001PLC047977\nGROUP DOMESTIC TRAVEL INSURANCE\nCHOTGDP23004V012223\nPolicy Wordings\nii. must not exceed the level of care necessary to provide safe, adequate and appropriate\nmedical care in scope, duration, or intensity;\niii. must have been prescribed by a Medical Practitioner;\nmust conform to the professional standards widely accepted in international medical practice or by the medical\ncommunity in India.\nNetwork Provider/ Hospital means Hospitals or health care providers enlisted by an insurer, TPA or jointly by an\nInsurer and TPA to provide medical services to an insured by a cashless facility.",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "3",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 5,
          "end": 6
        },
        {
          "text": "101",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 10,
          "end": 13
        },
        {
          "text": "GENERAL INSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED\nRegistered Office",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 31,
          "end": 82
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 109,
          "end": 110
        },
        {
          "text": "N.S.C. Bose Road",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 112,
          "end": 128
        },
        {
          "text": "Chennai",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 130,
          "end": 137
        },
        {
          "text": "600",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 140,
          "end": 143
        },
        {
          "text": "1800",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 160,
          "end": 164
        },
        {
          "text": "9100",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 169,
          "end": 173
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 183,
          "end": 184
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 186,
          "end": 188
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 208,
          "end": 209
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 211,
          "end": 213
        },
        {
          "text": "5550",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 219,
          "end": 223
        },
        {
          "text": "IRDA Regn",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 295,
          "end": 304
        },
        {
          "text": "PAN AABCC6633",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 314,
          "end": 327
        },
        {
          "text": "K CIN",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 327,
          "end": 332
        },
        {
          "text": "GROUP DOMESTIC TRAVEL INSURANCE",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 355,
          "end": 386
        },
        {
          "text": "Medical Practitioner",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 596,
          "end": 616
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 742,
          "end": 747
        },
        {
          "text": "Network Provider/ Hospital means Hospitals",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 749,
          "end": 791
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.0
    },
    {
      "text": "Insurer and TPA to provide medical services to an insured by a cashless facility.\nNon- Network means any hospital, day care centre or other provider that is not part of the network.\nNotification of claim means the process of intimating a claim to the insurer or TPA through any of the recognized\nmodes of communication.\nOPD treatment means is the one in which the Insured visits a clinic / hospital or associated facility like consultation\nroom for diagnosis and treatment based on the advice of a Medical Practitioner. The insured is not admitted as a day\ncare or in- patient. OPD to include emergency root canal treatment\nPre-existing Disease means any condition, ailment, injury or disease:\na) That is/are diagnosed by a physician within 48 months prior to the effective date of the policy issued by the\nInsurer or its reinstatement or\nb) For which medical advice or treatment was recommended by, or received from, a physician within 48 months",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Network",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 87,
          "end": 94
        },
        {
          "text": "OPD",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 320,
          "end": 323
        },
        {
          "text": "OPD",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 578,
          "end": 581
        },
        {
          "text": "48 months",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 741,
          "end": 750
        },
        {
          "text": "the\nInsurer",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 803,
          "end": 814
        },
        {
          "text": "48 months",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 937,
          "end": 946
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "Insurer or its reinstatement or\nb) For which medical advice or treatment was recommended by, or received from, a physician within 48 months\nprior to the effective date of the policy issued by the insurer or its reinstatement.\nQualified Nurse means a person who holds a valid registration from the Nursing Council of India or the Nursing\nCouncil of any state in India.\nReasonable and Customary Charges means the charges for services or supplies, which are the standard charges for\nthe specific provider and consistent with the prevailing charges in the geographical area for identical or similar\nservices, taking into account the nature of the illness / injury involved.\nRenewal means the terms on which the contract of insurance can be renewed on mutual consent with a provision of\ngrace period for treating the renewal continuous for the purpose gaining credit for pre-existing diseases, time-\nbound exclusions and for of all waiting periods.",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "48 months",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 130,
          "end": 139
        },
        {
          "text": "Qualified Nurse",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 226,
          "end": 241
        },
        {
          "text": "the Nursing Council of India",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 293,
          "end": 321
        },
        {
          "text": "the Nursing\nCouncil",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 325,
          "end": 344
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 361,
          "end": 366
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "bound exclusions and for of all waiting periods.\nSubrogation means the right of the insurer to assume the rights of the insured person to recover expenses paid out\nunder the policy that may be recovered from any other source.\nUnproven/ Experimental treatment means the treatment including drug experimental therapy which is not based\non established medical practice in India, is treatment experimental or unproven.\nB) SPECIFIC DEFINITIONS\nAir Travel means travel by an airline/aircraft for the purpose of flying therein as a Fare paying passenger.\nAlternative Treatments means forms of treatments other than treatment \"Allopathy\" or \"modern medicine\" and\nincludes Ayurveda, Unani, Siddha and Homeopathy in the Indian context.\nAppliances shall mean and include electrical, mechanical and electronic appliances used for household including\nwhilst in travel use\nAdventure Sports means and includes skydiving/parachuting, parasailing, hang gliding, paragliding, ballooning",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Unproven/ Experimental",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 226,
          "end": 248
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 369,
          "end": 374
        },
        {
          "text": "Air Travel",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 439,
          "end": 449
        },
        {
          "text": "Allopathy",
          "type": "WORK_OF_ART",
          "start": 619,
          "end": 628
        },
        {
          "text": "Unani",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 674,
          "end": 679
        },
        {
          "text": "Siddha",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 681,
          "end": 687
        },
        {
          "text": "Homeopathy",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 692,
          "end": 702
        },
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "type": "NORP",
          "start": 710,
          "end": 716
        },
        {
          "text": "Adventure Sports",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 859,
          "end": 875
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "whilst in travel use\nAdventure Sports means and includes skydiving/parachuting, parasailing, hang gliding, paragliding, ballooning\nbungee jumping, scuba diving, mountaineering or rock climbing (where ropes or guides are customarily used), Speed\ncontest or racing of any kind, caving or pot-holing, abseiling, hunting or equestrian activities, deep sea diving, skin\ndiving or other underwater activity, polo, snow and ice sports, rafting or canoeing involving white water rapids,\nyachting or boating, , Base Jumping, Ski Jumping, Trekking, Adventure racing on land and water, Snorkeling, Kayaking,\nSurfing, marathon running as a non-professional, biking, races as a non-professional, any bodily contact sport or any\nother hazardous or potentially dangerous sport.\nPage 4 of 101\nCHOLAMANDALAM MS GENERAL INSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED\nRegistered Office: 2nd Floor, “DARE House”, 2, N.S.C. Bose Road, Chennai – 600 001.\nToll free: 1800 208 9100, T: +91 (0) 44 4044 5400, F: +91 (0) 44 4044 5550",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Adventure Sports",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 21,
          "end": 37
        },
        {
          "text": "scuba",
          "type": "NORP",
          "start": 147,
          "end": 152
        },
        {
          "text": "rapids",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 471,
          "end": 477
        },
        {
          "text": "Base Jumping",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 502,
          "end": 514
        },
        {
          "text": "4",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 768,
          "end": 769
        },
        {
          "text": "101",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 773,
          "end": 776
        },
        {
          "text": "GENERAL INSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED\nRegistered Office",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 794,
          "end": 845
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 872,
          "end": 873
        },
        {
          "text": "N.S.C. Bose Road",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 875,
          "end": 891
        },
        {
          "text": "Chennai",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 893,
          "end": 900
        },
        {
          "text": "600",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 903,
          "end": 906
        },
        {
          "text": "1800",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 923,
          "end": 927
        },
        {
          "text": "9100",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 932,
          "end": 936
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 946,
          "end": 947
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 949,
          "end": 951
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 971,
          "end": 972
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 974,
          "end": 976
        },
        {
          "text": "5550",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 982,
          "end": 986
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "Toll free: 1800 208 9100, T: +91 (0) 44 4044 5400, F: +91 (0) 44 4044 5550\nE: customercare@cholams.murugappa.com; website: www.cholainsurance.com\nIRDA Regn. No.123; PAN AABCC6633K CIN U66030TN2001PLC047977\nGROUP DOMESTIC TRAVEL INSURANCE\nCHOTGDP23004V012223\nPolicy Wordings\nAssistance Service Provider means Third Party administrator or any organization or institution appointed by the\nCompany, for providing services to the Insured Person for an Insured Event covered.\nBaggage shall mean articles and / or personal effects of the Insured (other than property of the Business) in packing\nor in containers suitable and standard to the mode of Travel that is accompanied by the Insured or whilst such Baggage\nis lodged either in a locked private room of a hotel or guest house or any other accommodation occupied by the\nInsured during the Insured's stay at that location or in a public locker facility availed by the Insured during the course\nof or at any intermediate stage of the Travel.",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "COVERAGE",
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "1800",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 11,
          "end": 15
        },
        {
          "text": "9100",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 20,
          "end": 24
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 34,
          "end": 35
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 37,
          "end": 39
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 59,
          "end": 60
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 62,
          "end": 64
        },
        {
          "text": "5550",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 70,
          "end": 74
        },
        {
          "text": "IRDA Regn",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 146,
          "end": 155
        },
        {
          "text": "PAN AABCC6633",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 165,
          "end": 178
        },
        {
          "text": "K CIN",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 178,
          "end": 183
        },
        {
          "text": "GROUP DOMESTIC TRAVEL INSURANCE",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 206,
          "end": 237
        },
        {
          "text": "Wordings\nAssistance Service Provider",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 265,
          "end": 301
        },
        {
          "text": "Third Party",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 308,
          "end": 319
        },
        {
          "text": "the\nCompany",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 382,
          "end": 393
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured Person for an Insured Event",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 421,
          "end": 460
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 531,
          "end": 538
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 676,
          "end": 683
        },
        {
          "text": "Baggage",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 699,
          "end": 706
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 837,
          "end": 844
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 915,
          "end": 922
        },
        {
          "text": "Travel",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 980,
          "end": 986
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.0
    },
    {
      "text": "of or at any intermediate stage of the Travel.\nBase Sum Insured means the Sum Insured as specified in the Policy Schedule/Certificate against the respective base\ncovers.\nBurglary means theft involving entry into or exit from the Insured Person’s home in India by forcible and violent means\nor following assault or violence or threat thereof, to the Insured Person or to any Immediate Family Member or any\nperson residing lawfully in the Insured Person’s residence, with intent to commit a felony therein and includes\nhousebreaking.\nChecked-in Baggage means each suitcase or baggage handed over by the Insured Person and accepted by a Common\nCarrier for transportation in the same Common Carrier in which the Insured Person is or would be travelling, and for\nwhich the Common Carrier has issued a baggage receipt to the Insured Person. Checked-in Baggage excludes all items\nthat are carried/ transported under any contract of affreightment.",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Travel",
          "type": "LOC",
          "start": 39,
          "end": 45
        },
        {
          "text": "the Sum Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 70,
          "end": 85
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Schedule/Certificate",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 102,
          "end": 133
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured Person’s",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 225,
          "end": 245
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 254,
          "end": 259
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 345,
          "end": 363
        },
        {
          "text": "Immediate Family",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 374,
          "end": 390
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured Person’s",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 433,
          "end": 453
        },
        {
          "text": "Baggage",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 543,
          "end": 550
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 597,
          "end": 615
        },
        {
          "text": "a Common\nCarrier",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 632,
          "end": 648
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 704,
          "end": 722
        },
        {
          "text": "the Common Carrier",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 764,
          "end": 782
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 815,
          "end": 833
        },
        {
          "text": "Baggage",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 846,
          "end": 853
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "that are carried/ transported under any contract of affreightment.\nCommon Carrier means any transport means by civilian land, rail, water or Scheduled Airline in each case operated\nunder a valid license for the transportation of passengers for hire.\nContents mean and include electrical and electronic equipment, household appliances, furniture, fixture, fittings,\nlinen, clothing, interior decorations, kitchen items, cutlery /crockery contained in the Insured's home belonging to the\nInsured or his/her family members permanently residing with the Insured including items for which the Insured is\nresponsible, and used for domestic use. However, this does not include deeds, bonds, bills of exchange, promissory\nnotes, cheques, traveller's cheques, and securities for money, documents of any kind, cash, and currency notes.\nCorporate means any organization, firm, society or body corporate on whose name the policy is issued.",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Scheduled Airline",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 141,
          "end": 158
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 454,
          "end": 461
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 550,
          "end": 557
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 588,
          "end": 595
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "Corporate means any organization, firm, society or body corporate on whose name the policy is issued.\nDependent Child refers to a child (natural or legally adopted), below the age of 23 years, who is financially dependent\non the primary insured or proposer and does not have his / her independent sources of income.\nDisease means an alteration in the state of the body or of some of its organs interrupting or disrupting the\nperformance of the functions, and causing or threatening pain and weakness or physical or mental disorder and\ncertified by a Medical Practitioner.\nFamily means the Insured, his/her lawful spouse and maximum of any two dependent children up to the age of 25\nyears, parents, parents-in laws, siblings, children’s in laws, partner\nFelonious Assault means an act of violence against the Insured Person or a Travelling Companion requiring medical\ntreatment.\nFinancial Emergency means a situation where in the Insured Person loses all or a substantial amount of his/her travel",
      "type": "LIMITATION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "LIMITATION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Dependent Child",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 102,
          "end": 117
        },
        {
          "text": "the age of 23 years",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 172,
          "end": 191
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 589,
          "end": 596
        },
        {
          "text": "two",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 639,
          "end": 642
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured Person or a",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 804,
          "end": 827
        },
        {
          "text": "Travelling Companion",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 828,
          "end": 848
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 925,
          "end": 943
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "treatment.\nFinancial Emergency means a situation where in the Insured Person loses all or a substantial amount of his/her travel\nfunds due to theft, robbery, mugging or dacoity, which has detrimental effects on his/her travel plans.\nGroup A group should consist of persons who assemble together with a commonality of purpose or engaging in a\ncommon economic activity like employees of a company. It includes non-employer–employee groups like employee\nwelfare associations, co-operative society’s, Group policies being taken by Government bodies for certain\nidentifiable groups, credit/debit card/kisan credit card holders insured through the card issuance company,\ncustomers of a particular business, professional associations, borrowers/depositors of a bank, customers of a bank\nor aggregators, or members of any similar group being administered by a group administration wherein Insurance\nis being provided as an add-on benefit.",
      "type": "COVERAGE",
      "subtypes": [
        "COVERAGE",
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "the Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 58,
          "end": 76
        },
        {
          "text": "Group",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 497,
          "end": 502
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "is being provided as an add-on benefit.\nHazardous Occupation means persons whilst working in underground mines, explosives, magazines, workers whilst\ninvolved in electrical installation with high tension supply, jockeys, circus personnel, Aircraft pilots and crew, armed\nPage 5 of 101\nCHOLAMANDALAM MS GENERAL INSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED\nRegistered Office: 2nd Floor, “DARE House”, 2, N.S.C. Bose Road, Chennai – 600 001.\nToll free: 1800 208 9100, T: +91 (0) 44 4044 5400, F: +91 (0) 44 4044 5550\nE: customercare@cholams.murugappa.com; website: www.cholainsurance.com\nIRDA Regn. No.123; PAN AABCC6633K CIN U66030TN2001PLC047977\nGROUP DOMESTIC TRAVEL INSURANCE\nCHOTGDP23004V012223\nPolicy Wordings\nforces personnel, artistes engaged in hazardous performances, aerial crop sprayer, Demolition contractor, explosives\nusers, Fisherman (Seagoing, Jockey, Marine Salvager, Miner and other occupations underground, nuclear",
      "type": "COVERAGE",
      "subtypes": [
        "COVERAGE",
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Hazardous Occupation",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 40,
          "end": 60
        },
        {
          "text": "Aircraft",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 239,
          "end": 247
        },
        {
          "text": "5",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 276,
          "end": 277
        },
        {
          "text": "101",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 281,
          "end": 284
        },
        {
          "text": "GENERAL INSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED\nRegistered Office",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 302,
          "end": 353
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 380,
          "end": 381
        },
        {
          "text": "N.S.C. Bose Road",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 383,
          "end": 399
        },
        {
          "text": "Chennai",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 401,
          "end": 408
        },
        {
          "text": "600",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 411,
          "end": 414
        },
        {
          "text": "1800",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 431,
          "end": 435
        },
        {
          "text": "9100",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 440,
          "end": 444
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 454,
          "end": 455
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 457,
          "end": 459
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 479,
          "end": 480
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 482,
          "end": 484
        },
        {
          "text": "5550",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 490,
          "end": 494
        },
        {
          "text": "IRDA Regn",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 566,
          "end": 575
        },
        {
          "text": "PAN AABCC6633",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 585,
          "end": 598
        },
        {
          "text": "K CIN",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 598,
          "end": 603
        },
        {
          "text": "GROUP DOMESTIC TRAVEL INSURANCE",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 626,
          "end": 657
        },
        {
          "text": "Fisherman",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 818,
          "end": 827
        },
        {
          "text": "Salvager",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 854,
          "end": 862
        },
        {
          "text": "Miner",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 864,
          "end": 869
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "users, Fisherman (Seagoing, Jockey, Marine Salvager, Miner and other occupations underground, nuclear\ninstallations, Off-shore oil or gas rig worker, professional sports person, roofing contractors and all construction,\nmaintenance and repair workers at heights in excess of 50ft/15m, saw miller, scaffolder, ship crew, steeplejack,\nstevedore, structural steelworker, tower crane operator, tree feller.\nHijack means any unlawful seizure or exercise of control, by force or violence or threat of force or violence and with\nwrongful intent, of the Common Carrier in which the Insured Person is travelling.\nHousebreaking means an act involving physical break-in and unauthorized and forcible entry into Insured Person's\nhome in India, or any threat, with intent to commit crime.\nImmediate family member shall mean any member of the Insured Person's immediate family i.e the Insured\nPerson's spouse, children, parents, parents in law, Children in law, sibling, partner or travelling companion.",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Fisherman",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 7,
          "end": 16
        },
        {
          "text": "Salvager",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 43,
          "end": 51
        },
        {
          "text": "Miner",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 53,
          "end": 58
        },
        {
          "text": "50ft/15",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 275,
          "end": 282
        },
        {
          "text": "miller",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 289,
          "end": 295
        },
        {
          "text": "the Common Carrier",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 542,
          "end": 560
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 570,
          "end": 588
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured Person's",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 700,
          "end": 716
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 725,
          "end": 730
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured Person's",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 825,
          "end": 845
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured\nPerson's",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 867,
          "end": 887
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.0
    },
    {
      "text": "Person's spouse, children, parents, parents in law, Children in law, sibling, partner or travelling companion.\nInclement Weather means any severe catastrophic weather conditions which delay the scheduled arrival or\ndeparture of a Common Carrier but not including normal, seasonal/climatic weather changes.\nInsured/Insured Person means the person named in the Policy Schedule, who has a permanent place of residence in\nIndia and for whom the insurance is proposed and appropriate premium paid. It includes foreign travelers having\ntraveler visa.\nInsured Event means an event, loss or damage specifically described as covered and for which the Insured Person is\nentitled to benefit/s under this Policy.\nLand/Sea Arrangements means pre-paid travel arrangements for a scheduled tour, trip or cruise included within the\ndescription of covered Trips on the Proposal/Enrollment and Declaration Form and arranged by a tour operator, travel\nagent, or other organization.",
      "type": "COVERAGE",
      "subtypes": [
        "COVERAGE",
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Inclement Weather",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 111,
          "end": 128
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured/Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 306,
          "end": 328
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Schedule",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 355,
          "end": 374
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 418,
          "end": 423
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured Event",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 545,
          "end": 558
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 638,
          "end": 656
        },
        {
          "text": "Land/Sea Arrangements",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 701,
          "end": 722
        },
        {
          "text": "Trips",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 838,
          "end": 843
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.6666666666666666
    },
    {
      "text": "description of covered Trips on the Proposal/Enrollment and Declaration Form and arranged by a tour operator, travel\nagent, or other organization.\nLife threatening condition / situation” refers to a medical condition suffered by the Insured which has the following\ncharacteristics:\ni. Markedly unstable vital parameters (blood pressure, pulse, temperature and respiratory rate).\nii. Acute impairment of one or more vital organ systems (involving brain, heart, lungs, Liver, Kidneys and pancreas).\niii. Critical care being provided, which involves high complexity decision making to assess, manipulate and support vital\nsystem function(s) to treat single or multiple vital organ failure(s) and requires interpretation of multiple physiological\nparameters and application of advanced technology.\niv. Critical care being provided in critical care area such as coronary care unit, intensive care unit, respiratory care unit,\nor the emergency department.\nLoss means loss or damage.",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "COVERAGE",
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Trips",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 23,
          "end": 28
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 233,
          "end": 240
        },
        {
          "text": "one",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 403,
          "end": 406
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "or the emergency department.\nLoss means loss or damage.\nMan days is a 24 hours’ period starting from midnight for an individual whilst travelling within the territorial\nboundaries of India.\nMaster Policy Schedule/Policy Schedule means schedule attached to and forming part of this Policy, mentioning the\ndetails of the Proposer / Group Manager, the Sum Insured, Period and limits to which benefits under the policy\nwould be payable.\nMulti trip means two or more trips to destinations of Republic of India during the Policy period.\nNatural Teeth means natural teeth that is unaltered or is fully restored to their normal function and is Disease-free,\nhave no decay and are not more susceptible to Injury than unaltered natural teeth.\nPeriod of Insurance in respect of Single Trip Policy means the period from the commencement date of the insurance\ncover to the Risk end Date as specified in the Policy Schedule/certificate or on the date when the insured returns to",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "COVERAGE",
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Man days",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 56,
          "end": 64
        },
        {
          "text": "24 hours",
          "type": "TIME",
          "start": 70,
          "end": 78
        },
        {
          "text": "midnight",
          "type": "TIME",
          "start": 101,
          "end": 109
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 183,
          "end": 188
        },
        {
          "text": "the Proposer / Group",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 315,
          "end": 335
        },
        {
          "text": "the Sum Insured, Period",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 345,
          "end": 368
        },
        {
          "text": "two",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 450,
          "end": 453
        },
        {
          "text": "Republic of India",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 487,
          "end": 504
        },
        {
          "text": "Injury",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 696,
          "end": 702
        },
        {
          "text": "the Risk end Date",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 856,
          "end": 873
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Schedule",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 890,
          "end": 909
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.6666666666666666
    },
    {
      "text": "cover to the Risk end Date as specified in the Policy Schedule/certificate or on the date when the insured returns to\nhis/her usual town of residence or the date of cancellation of the insurance, whichever is earlier\nPeriod of Insurance in respect of the Multi Trip/ Annual policy shall mean the period from Commencement of\nInsurance cover to the end of the insurance cover or full utilization of the maximum number of travel days per trip as\nmentioned in Policy Schedule/Certificate, or expiry of the Policy or cancellation of the insurance, whichever is earlier.\nPage 6 of 101\nCHOLAMANDALAM MS GENERAL INSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED\nRegistered Office: 2nd Floor, “DARE House”, 2, N.S.C. Bose Road, Chennai – 600 001.\nToll free: 1800 208 9100, T: +91 (0) 44 4044 5400, F: +91 (0) 44 4044 5550\nE: customercare@cholams.murugappa.com; website: www.cholainsurance.com\nIRDA Regn. No.123; PAN AABCC6633K CIN U66030TN2001PLC047977\nGROUP DOMESTIC TRAVEL INSURANCE\nCHOTGDP23004V012223\nPolicy Wordings",
      "type": "LIMITATION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION",
        "LIMITATION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "the Risk end Date",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 9,
          "end": 26
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Schedule",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 43,
          "end": 62
        },
        {
          "text": "Multi Trip/",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 255,
          "end": 266
        },
        {
          "text": "Annual",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 267,
          "end": 273
        },
        {
          "text": "Policy Schedule/Certificate",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 456,
          "end": 483
        },
        {
          "text": "Policy",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 502,
          "end": 508
        },
        {
          "text": "6",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 570,
          "end": 571
        },
        {
          "text": "101",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 575,
          "end": 578
        },
        {
          "text": "GENERAL INSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED\nRegistered Office",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 596,
          "end": 647
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 674,
          "end": 675
        },
        {
          "text": "N.S.C. Bose Road",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 677,
          "end": 693
        },
        {
          "text": "Chennai",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 695,
          "end": 702
        },
        {
          "text": "600",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 705,
          "end": 708
        },
        {
          "text": "1800",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 725,
          "end": 729
        },
        {
          "text": "9100",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 734,
          "end": 738
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 748,
          "end": 749
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 751,
          "end": 753
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 773,
          "end": 774
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 776,
          "end": 778
        },
        {
          "text": "5550",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 784,
          "end": 788
        },
        {
          "text": "IRDA Regn",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 860,
          "end": 869
        },
        {
          "text": "PAN AABCC6633",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 879,
          "end": 892
        },
        {
          "text": "K CIN",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 892,
          "end": 897
        },
        {
          "text": "GROUP DOMESTIC TRAVEL INSURANCE",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 920,
          "end": 951
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.6666666666666666
    },
    {
      "text": "IRDA Regn. No.123; PAN AABCC6633K CIN U66030TN2001PLC047977\nGROUP DOMESTIC TRAVEL INSURANCE\nCHOTGDP23004V012223\nPolicy Wordings\nPhysician means a licensed medical practitioner acting within the scope of his license and who holds a degree of a\nrecognized institution and is registered by the Medical Council of India. The term Physician would include specialist and\nsurgeon. Family members are excluded from the Definition of Physician.\nPolicy means proposal, the Schedule/Certificate, the Policy documents and any endorsements attaching to or\nforming part hereof either on the commencement date or during the Policy Period.\nPolicy Certificate means the document giving mentioning the name of the Insured / Insured persons, Policy Period,\nscope of cover, limits to which benefits are subject to and other relevant terms and conditions.\nPermanent Partial Disablement means a bodily injury caused by accidental, external, violent and visible means,",
      "type": "EXCLUSION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "EXCLUSION",
        "LIMITATION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "IRDA Regn",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 9
        },
        {
          "text": "PAN AABCC6633",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 19,
          "end": 32
        },
        {
          "text": "K CIN",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 32,
          "end": 37
        },
        {
          "text": "GROUP DOMESTIC TRAVEL INSURANCE",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 60,
          "end": 91
        },
        {
          "text": "the Medical Council of India",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 287,
          "end": 315
        },
        {
          "text": "Physician",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 326,
          "end": 335
        },
        {
          "text": "the Definition of Physician",
          "type": "LAW",
          "start": 407,
          "end": 434
        },
        {
          "text": "the Schedule/Certificate",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 459,
          "end": 483
        },
        {
          "text": "Policy",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 489,
          "end": 495
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Period",
          "type": "LAW",
          "start": 605,
          "end": 622
        },
        {
          "text": "Policy Certificate",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 624,
          "end": 642
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured / Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 692,
          "end": 713
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "Permanent Partial Disablement means a bodily injury caused by accidental, external, violent and visible means,\nwhich as a direct consequence thereof, disables any part of the limbs or organs of the body of the insured/insured\nperson and which falls into one of the categories listed in the Table of benefits.\nPermanent Total Disablement” means a bodily injury caused by accidental, external, violent and visible means, which\nas a direct consequence thereof totally disables and prevents the insured from attending to any business or occupation\nof any and every kind or if he/she has no business or occupation, from attending to his/her usual and normal duties\nthat last for a continuous period of twelve calendar months from the date of the accident, with no hopes of\nimprovement at the end of that period.\nPre-existing Disability means an existing disability and consequence of such disability existing or known to exist at\nthe commencement of the policy period.",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "twelve",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 697,
          "end": 703
        },
        {
          "text": "months",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 713,
          "end": 719
        },
        {
          "text": "Disability",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 820,
          "end": 830
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "the commencement of the policy period.\nProfessional Sportsperson means those sports persons who are in to full time sports and maintain their livelihood\nthrough earnings from their involvement in sports.\nReasonable Additional Expenses means any expenses for meals and lodging necessarily incurred by the\nInsured/Insured Person as a result of a trip delay but does not include meals and lodging provided by the common\ncarrier or any other party free of charge.\nReturn Destination means the place to which the Insured/Insured Person is scheduled to return from his/her trip.\nScheduled Airline means any civilian aircraft operated by a civilian scheduled air carrier holding a certificate, license or\nsimilar authorization for civilian scheduled air carrier transport issued by the country of the aircraft’s registry, and\nwhich in accordance therewith flies, maintains and publishes tariffs for regular passenger service between named",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Sportsperson",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 52,
          "end": 64
        },
        {
          "text": "the\nInsured/Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 300,
          "end": 326
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured/Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 504,
          "end": 530
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "which in accordance therewith flies, maintains and publishes tariffs for regular passenger service between named\ncities at regular and specified times, on regular or chartered flights operated by such carrier.\nSchedule Railways means any Railways operated by Indian Railways, which in accordance there with operates,\nmaintains and publishes tariffs for regular passenger service between named cities at regular and specified times, on\nregular journey operated by such carrier.\nSchedule Roadways means a roadways carrier which is operated between named cities under a valid license issued\nby the appropriate Indian governmental authority for the transportation of passengers within India for a fee, and\nwhich maintains and publishes regular tariffs for regular passenger services which it operates between named cities\nat regular and specified times\nSemiprofessional sports person shall mean those sports persons who participate in sports on frequent basis (at least",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Schedule Railways means any Railways",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 210,
          "end": 246
        },
        {
          "text": "Indian Railways",
          "type": "LOC",
          "start": 259,
          "end": 274
        },
        {
          "text": "Schedule Roadways",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 477,
          "end": 494
        },
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "type": "NORP",
          "start": 607,
          "end": 613
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 681,
          "end": 686
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "at regular and specified times\nSemiprofessional sports person shall mean those sports persons who participate in sports on frequent basis (at least\nonce in a month) while being separately employed elsewhere or self-employed and whose primary source of income\nis not from sports.\nStrike means stoppage of work (a) announced, organized and sanctioned by a labour union and (b) which interferes\nwith the normal departure and arrival of a common carrier inclusive of work slowdowns, lockouts and sickouts.\nSum Insured means the maximum amount of coverage, as specified in the Policy Schedule/certificate, that the\nInsured/Insured Person is entitled to in respect of each benefit and as applicable under the Policy.\nSurgery or Surgical Procedure means manual and / or operative procedure (s) required for treatment of an illness or\ninjury, correction of deformities and defects, diagnosis and cure of diseases, relief from suffering or prolongation of",
      "type": "LIMITATION",
      "subtypes": [
        "COVERAGE",
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION",
        "LIMITATION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "a month",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 156,
          "end": 163
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Schedule",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 568,
          "end": 587
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "injury, correction of deformities and defects, diagnosis and cure of diseases, relief from suffering or prolongation of\nlife, performed in a hospital or day care center by a medical practitioner.\nPage 7 of 101\nCHOLAMANDALAM MS GENERAL INSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED\nRegistered Office: 2nd Floor, “DARE House”, 2, N.S.C. Bose Road, Chennai – 600 001.\nToll free: 1800 208 9100, T: +91 (0) 44 4044 5400, F: +91 (0) 44 4044 5550\nE: customercare@cholams.murugappa.com; website: www.cholainsurance.com\nIRDA Regn. No.123; PAN AABCC6633K CIN U66030TN2001PLC047977\nGROUP DOMESTIC TRAVEL INSURANCE\nCHOTGDP23004V012223\nPolicy Wordings\nTerrorism/Terrorist Incident means any actual or threatened use of force or violence directed at or causing damage,\ninjury, harm or disruption, or the commission of an act dangerous to human life or property, against any individual,\nproperty or government, with the stated or unstated objective of pursuing economic, ethnic, nationalistic, political,",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "7",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 201,
          "end": 202
        },
        {
          "text": "101",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 206,
          "end": 209
        },
        {
          "text": "GENERAL INSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED\nRegistered Office",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 227,
          "end": 278
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 305,
          "end": 306
        },
        {
          "text": "N.S.C. Bose Road",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 308,
          "end": 324
        },
        {
          "text": "Chennai",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 326,
          "end": 333
        },
        {
          "text": "600",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 336,
          "end": 339
        },
        {
          "text": "1800",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 356,
          "end": 360
        },
        {
          "text": "9100",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 365,
          "end": 369
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 379,
          "end": 380
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 382,
          "end": 384
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 404,
          "end": 405
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 407,
          "end": 409
        },
        {
          "text": "5550",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 415,
          "end": 419
        },
        {
          "text": "IRDA Regn",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 491,
          "end": 500
        },
        {
          "text": "PAN AABCC6633",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 510,
          "end": 523
        },
        {
          "text": "K CIN",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 523,
          "end": 528
        },
        {
          "text": "GROUP DOMESTIC TRAVEL INSURANCE",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 551,
          "end": 582
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "property or government, with the stated or unstated objective of pursuing economic, ethnic, nationalistic, political,\nracial or religious interests, whether such interests are declared or not. Robberies or other criminal acts, primarily\ncommitted for personal gain and acts arising primarily from prior personal relationships between perpetrator(s) and\nvictim(s) shall not be considered terrorist activity. Terrorism shall also include any act, which is verified or recognized\nby the relevant Government as an act of terrorism.\nTravel Agent means the Travel Agent, tour operator or other entity from which the Insured purchases his/her\ninsurance Policy or travel arrangements, and includes all officers, employees and affiliates of the Travel Agent, tour\noperator or other entity.\nTravelling Companion means an individual or individuals travelling with the Insured/Insured Person, provided that,",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Travel Agent",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 528,
          "end": 540
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 610,
          "end": 617
        },
        {
          "text": "Travelling Companion",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 781,
          "end": 801
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured/Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 853,
          "end": 879
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.6666666666666666
    },
    {
      "text": "operator or other entity.\nTravelling Companion means an individual or individuals travelling with the Insured/Insured Person, provided that,\nthe Insured and such individual(s) are travelling to the same destination and on the same date and such individual(s)\nis/are also insured under this Policy. For the purpose of this definition, any individual(s) forming part of a group\ntravelling on a tour arranged by a Travel Agent or a tour operator shall not be considered as Travelling Companion,\nunless the individual(s) is/are part of the family of the Insured/Insured Person.\nTerritory: This Policy applies to incidents anywhere in India while travelling.\n“Trip” means a journey out of usual place of residence in India and back, the details of which are specified in the Policy\nSchedule/Certificate.\nIncludes Business and Leisure trips both unless specified otherwise\n\nCoverage for a Trip involving travel by <<Air/Rail/Road/Water>> will be as specified in the policy schedule/Certificate\n",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Travelling Companion",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 26,
          "end": 46
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured/Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 98,
          "end": 124
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 145,
          "end": 152
        },
        {
          "text": "Travelling Companion",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 470,
          "end": 490
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured/Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 546,
          "end": 572
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 630,
          "end": 635
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 712,
          "end": 717
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy\nSchedule/Certificate",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 766,
          "end": 797
        },
        {
          "text": "Air/Rail/Road/Water",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 911,
          "end": 930
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.6666666666666666
    },
    {
      "text": "\nCoverage for a Trip involving travel by <<Air/Rail/Road/Water>> will be as specified in the policy schedule/Certificate\n\nwhich commences when the passenger boards the Common Carrier, including Private Vehicle for onward journey\n\nand terminates when he disembarks on return to Your usual Town of residence or the contracted date whichever\nearlier\nThe insured journey also includes and covers Sojourn and/or Personal Deviation.\n\nUnattended: A Vehicle, premises or personal belongings are unattended if there is no one able to observe or to prevent\ninterference with it.\nValuables means photographic, audio, video, computer and any other electronic equipment, telecommunications\nand electrical equipment, telescopes, binoculars, antiques, watches, perfumes, Jewellery, furs and articles made\nof precious stones and metals.\nWar means war, whether declared or not, or any warlike activities, including use of military force by any sovereign",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Air/Rail/Road/Water",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 44,
          "end": 63
        },
        {
          "text": "the Common Carrier",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 166,
          "end": 184
        },
        {
          "text": "Private Vehicle",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 196,
          "end": 211
        },
        {
          "text": "Sojourn and/or Personal Deviation",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 395,
          "end": 428
        },
        {
          "text": "Jewellery",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 760,
          "end": 769
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.6666666666666666
    },
    {
      "text": "of precious stones and metals.\nWar means war, whether declared or not, or any warlike activities, including use of military force by any sovereign\nnation to achieve economic, geographic, nationalistic, political, racial, religious or other ends.",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "2. PERSONS WHO CAN BE INSURED:\n This Insurance is available for persons who is an employee or member of the Policyholder and his family\nmembers having a permanent place of residence in India and for whom the insurance is proposed and\nappropriate premium paid.\n Entry age for the member should be between 03 months to 90 years (completed age).",
      "type": "GENERAL",
      "subtypes": [],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 1
        },
        {
          "text": "",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 31,
          "end": 32
        },
        {
          "text": "Policyholder",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 109,
          "end": 121
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 186,
          "end": 191
        },
        {
          "text": "",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 261,
          "end": 262
        },
        {
          "text": "between 03 months to 90 years",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 298,
          "end": 327
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "3. COVERAGE - BASE COVERS:\nThe Policy provides the following Base Covers. It is mandatory for the proposer/Insured to avail the Base Cover to\nbe eligible for taking this Policy from Cholamandalam MS General Insurance Company Limited. Various Base and\nOptional Covers applicable for the Insured under this policy is as shown in the Policy Schedule/Certificate.\nPage 8 of 101\nCHOLAMANDALAM MS GENERAL INSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED\nRegistered Office: 2nd Floor, “DARE House”, 2, N.S.C. Bose Road, Chennai – 600 001.\nToll free: 1800 208 9100, T: +91 (0) 44 4044 5400, F: +91 (0) 44 4044 5550\nE: customercare@cholams.murugappa.com; website: www.cholainsurance.com\nIRDA Regn. No.123; PAN AABCC6633K CIN U66030TN2001PLC047977\nGROUP DOMESTIC TRAVEL INSURANCE\nCHOTGDP23004V012223\nPolicy Wordings\nThe Company hereby agrees subject to the terms, conditions and exclusions herein contained or otherwise expressed,",
      "type": "LIMITATION",
      "subtypes": [
        "COVERAGE",
        "LIMITATION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "3",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 1
        },
        {
          "text": "Cholamandalam MS General Insurance Company Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 182,
          "end": 232
        },
        {
          "text": "Optional Covers",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 251,
          "end": 266
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 286,
          "end": 293
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Schedule/Certificate",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 327,
          "end": 358
        },
        {
          "text": "8",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 365,
          "end": 366
        },
        {
          "text": "101",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 370,
          "end": 373
        },
        {
          "text": "GENERAL INSURANCE COMPANY LIMITED\nRegistered Office",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 391,
          "end": 442
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 469,
          "end": 470
        },
        {
          "text": "N.S.C. Bose Road",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 472,
          "end": 488
        },
        {
          "text": "Chennai",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 490,
          "end": 497
        },
        {
          "text": "600",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 500,
          "end": 503
        },
        {
          "text": "1800",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 520,
          "end": 524
        },
        {
          "text": "9100",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 529,
          "end": 533
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 543,
          "end": 544
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 546,
          "end": 548
        },
        {
          "text": "0",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 568,
          "end": 569
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 571,
          "end": 573
        },
        {
          "text": "5550",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 579,
          "end": 583
        },
        {
          "text": "IRDA Regn",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 655,
          "end": 664
        },
        {
          "text": "PAN AABCC6633",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 674,
          "end": 687
        },
        {
          "text": "K CIN",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 687,
          "end": 692
        },
        {
          "text": "GROUP DOMESTIC TRAVEL INSURANCE",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 715,
          "end": 746
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "Policy Wordings\nThe Company hereby agrees subject to the terms, conditions and exclusions herein contained or otherwise expressed,\nto compensate, indemnify, pay and/or reimburse in manner provided in this policy, benefits to the insured for loss\nor damage described hereunder as per the coverage and up to the limit of Sum Insured specified in the Policy\nSchedule.\nClaims made under any applicable cover for the Period of Insurance will be subject to the terms, conditions and\nexclusions of this Policy Wording, the availability of the Sum Insured for that Cover, any applicable sub-limits and/or\nDeductibles.\nThe Insurance policy will commence from the date and time as mentioned in the Policy Schedule/Certificate and\nend on the date and time as printed on the Policy Schedule/Certificate, unless specified otherwise under the\nrespective cover.\nSl. No. BASE COVERS\n1 Emergency Accidental Hospitalization\n2 OPD Treatment\nPersonal Accident Covers\na. Accidental Death\n3",
      "type": "LIMITATION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "LIMITATION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "the Policy\nSchedule",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 344,
          "end": 363
        },
        {
          "text": "the Period of Insurance",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 408,
          "end": 431
        },
        {
          "text": "the Sum Insured for that Cover",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 532,
          "end": 562
        },
        {
          "text": "Insurance",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 614,
          "end": 623
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Schedule/Certificate",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 684,
          "end": 715
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Schedule/Certificate",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 759,
          "end": 790
        },
        {
          "text": "Sl",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 847,
          "end": 849
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 867,
          "end": 868
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 906,
          "end": 907
        },
        {
          "text": "a. Accidental Death\n",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 947,
          "end": 967
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 967,
          "end": 968
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "respective cover.\nSl. No. BASE COVERS\n1 Emergency Accidental Hospitalization\n2 OPD Treatment\nPersonal Accident Covers\na. Accidental Death\n3\nb. Permanent Total Disability (PTD)\nc. Permanent Partial Disability (PPD)",
      "type": "COVERAGE",
      "subtypes": [],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Sl",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 18,
          "end": 20
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 38,
          "end": 39
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 77,
          "end": 78
        },
        {
          "text": "a. Accidental Death\n3",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 118,
          "end": 139
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "1. EMERGENCY ACCIDENTAL HOSPITALISATION:\na. Coverage:\nThe policy shall reimburse the Reasonable and Customary Charges for Emergency Medical Expenses incurred in the\nRepublic of India by insured for immediate medical services as an In-Patient, due to any accidental injury up to the\nmaximum Sum Insured amount and for policy period as stated in the policy schedule. The treatment shall cover\nthe following.",
      "type": "LIMITATION",
      "subtypes": [
        "CONDITION",
        "LIMITATION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "1",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 1
        },
        {
          "text": "a. Coverage",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 41,
          "end": 52
        },
        {
          "text": "the\nRepublic of India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 161,
          "end": 182
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "1. In-patient treatment in a local hospital at the place where the Insured is staying at the time of the event;",
      "type": "GENERAL",
      "subtypes": [],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "1",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 1
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 67,
          "end": 74
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "2. X-ray, diagnostic tests and all reasonable costs towards diagnostic methods and treatment during\nhospitalisation.",
      "type": "GENERAL",
      "subtypes": [],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 1
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
