{
  "metadata": {
    "source_file": "HDFHLIP23024V072223.pdf",
    "policy_number": null,
    "effective_date": null,
    "coverage_types": [
      "health",
      "accident",
      "property",
      "liability",
      "auto"
    ],
    "file_info": {
      "path": "G:\\project\\life_insurence_query\\file_inputs\\HDFHLIP23024V072223.pdf",
      "last_modified": "2025-07-25 16:01:24.315145"
    }
  },
  "clauses": [
    {
      "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited\nEASY HEALTH\nPreamble\nHDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited will cover all Insured Persons under this Policy upto the\nSum Insured. The insurance cover is governed by, and subject to, the terms, conditions and exclusions of\nthis Policy.\nSection A. Other Important Terms You should know\nThe terms defined below and at other junctures in the Policy Wording have the meanings ascribed to\nthem wherever they appear in this Policy and, where appropriate, references to the singular include\nreferences to the plural; references to the male include the female and references to any statutory\nenactment include subsequent changes to the same:",
      "type": "LIMITATION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION",
        "LIMITATION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 43
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 65,
          "end": 108
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured Persons",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 124,
          "end": 139
        },
        {
          "text": "Policy",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 151,
          "end": 157
        },
        {
          "text": "Policy",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 467,
          "end": 473
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "1. Standard Definitions\nDef. 1. Accident means a sudden, unforeseen and involuntary event caused by external, visible and\nviolent means.\nDef. 2. Any one illness means continuous Period of illness and it includes relapse within 45 days\nfrom the date of last consultation with the Hospital/Nursing Home where treatment may\nhave been taken.\nDef. 3. AYUSH HOSPITAL means an AYUSH Hospital is a healthcare facility wherein\nmedical/surgical/para-surgical treatment procedures and interventions are carried out by\nAYUSH Medical Practitioner(s) comprising of any of the following:\na. Central or State Government AYUSH Hospital; or\nb. Teaching hospital attached to AYUSH College recognized by the Central Government\n/Central Council of Indian Medicine/Central Council for Homeopathy; or\nc. AYUSH Hospital, standalone or co-located within-patient healthcare facility of any\nrecognized system of medicine, registered with the local authorities, wherever",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "1",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 1
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 29,
          "end": 30
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 142,
          "end": 143
        },
        {
          "text": "one",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 149,
          "end": 152
        },
        {
          "text": "45 days",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 227,
          "end": 234
        },
        {
          "text": "the date of last",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 240,
          "end": 256
        },
        {
          "text": "the Hospital/Nursing Home",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 275,
          "end": 300
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 343,
          "end": 344
        },
        {
          "text": "an AYUSH Hospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 367,
          "end": 384
        },
        {
          "text": "Practitioner(s",
          "type": "NORP",
          "start": 521,
          "end": 535
        },
        {
          "text": "State Government AYUSH Hospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 587,
          "end": 618
        },
        {
          "text": "AYUSH College",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 656,
          "end": 669
        },
        {
          "text": "Council of Indian Medicine/Central Council",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 716,
          "end": 758
        },
        {
          "text": "Homeopathy",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 763,
          "end": 773
        },
        {
          "text": "c. AYUSH Hospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 778,
          "end": 795
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "recognized system of medicine, registered with the local authorities, wherever\napplicable, and is under the supervision of a qualified registered AYUSH Medical\nPractitioner and must comply with all the following criterion:\ni. Having at least 5 in-patient beds;\nii. Having qualified AYUSH Medical Practitioner in charge round the clock;\niii. Having dedicated AYUSH therapy sections as required and/or has equipped\noperation theatre where surgical procedures are to be carried out;\niv. Maintaining daily records of the patients and making them accessible to the\ninsurance company’s authorized representative.\nDef. 4. AYUSH Day Care Centre means and includes Community Health Centre (CHC), Primary\nHealth Centre (PHC), Dispensary, Clinic, Polyclinic or any such health centre which is registered\nwith the local authorities, wherever applicable and having facilities for carrying out treatment\nprocedures and medical or surgical/para-surgical interventions or both under the supervision of",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "at least 5",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 233,
          "end": 243
        },
        {
          "text": "daily",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 496,
          "end": 501
        },
        {
          "text": "4.",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 612,
          "end": 614
        },
        {
          "text": "Community Health Centre",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 656,
          "end": 679
        },
        {
          "text": "CHC",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 681,
          "end": 684
        },
        {
          "text": "Primary\nHealth Centre",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 687,
          "end": 708
        },
        {
          "text": "PHC",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 710,
          "end": 713
        },
        {
          "text": "Dispensary",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 716,
          "end": 726
        },
        {
          "text": "Clinic",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 728,
          "end": 734
        },
        {
          "text": "Polyclinic",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 736,
          "end": 746
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "procedures and medical or surgical/para-surgical interventions or both under the supervision of\nregistered AYUSH Medical Practitioner(s) on day care basis without in-patient services and must\ncomply with all the following criterion:\ni. Having qualified registered AYUSH Medical Practitioner (s) in charge;\nii. Having dedicated AYUSH therapy sections as required and/or has equipped operation\ntheatre where surgical procedures are to be carried out;\niii. Maintaining daily records of the patients and making them accessible to the insurance\ncompany’s authorized representative.\nDef. 5. Cashless facility means a facility extended by the insurer to the insured where the payments,\nof the costs of treatment undergone by the insured in accordance with the policy terms and\nHDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited. IRDAI Reg. No.146. CIN: U66030MH2007PLC177117. Registered &\nCorporate Office: 1st Floor, HDFC House, 165-166 Backbay Reclamation, H. T. Parekh Marg, Churchgate, Mumbai – 400",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Practitioner(s",
          "type": "NORP",
          "start": 121,
          "end": 135
        },
        {
          "text": "daily",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 466,
          "end": 471
        },
        {
          "text": "5",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 582,
          "end": 583
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 770,
          "end": 813
        },
        {
          "text": "IRDAI Reg",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 815,
          "end": 824
        },
        {
          "text": "CIN",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 834,
          "end": 837
        },
        {
          "text": "1st Floor",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 893,
          "end": 902
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC House",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 904,
          "end": 914
        },
        {
          "text": "165",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 916,
          "end": 919
        },
        {
          "text": "H. T. Parekh Marg",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 945,
          "end": 962
        },
        {
          "text": "Churchgate",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 964,
          "end": 974
        },
        {
          "text": "Mumbai",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 976,
          "end": 982
        },
        {
          "text": "400",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 985,
          "end": 988
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "Corporate Office: 1st Floor, HDFC House, 165-166 Backbay Reclamation, H. T. Parekh Marg, Churchgate, Mumbai – 400\n020. Trade Logo displayed above belongs to HDFC Ltd and ERGO International AG and used by the Company under\nlicense. Easy Health UIN: HDFHLIP23024V072223\n1 | P age\nHDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited\nconditions, are directly made to the network provider by the insurer to the extent pre-\nauthorization approved.\nDef. 6. Condition Precedent means a policy term or condition upon which the Insurer’s liability\nunder the policy is conditional upon.\nDef. 7. Congenital Anomaly refers to a condition(s) which is present since birth, and which is\nabnormal with reference to form, structure or position",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Corporate Office",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 16
        },
        {
          "text": "1st Floor",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 18,
          "end": 27
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC House",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 29,
          "end": 39
        },
        {
          "text": "165",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 41,
          "end": 44
        },
        {
          "text": "H. T. Parekh Marg",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 70,
          "end": 87
        },
        {
          "text": "Churchgate",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 89,
          "end": 99
        },
        {
          "text": "Mumbai",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 101,
          "end": 107
        },
        {
          "text": "400",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 110,
          "end": 113
        },
        {
          "text": "020",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 114,
          "end": 117
        },
        {
          "text": "Trade Logo",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 119,
          "end": 129
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC Ltd",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 157,
          "end": 165
        },
        {
          "text": "ERGO International AG",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 170,
          "end": 191
        },
        {
          "text": "Company",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 208,
          "end": 215
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 268,
          "end": 269
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 278,
          "end": 321
        },
        {
          "text": "6",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 439,
          "end": 440
        },
        {
          "text": "Insurer",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 510,
          "end": 517
        },
        {
          "text": "7",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 573,
          "end": 574
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "(a) Internal Congenital Anomaly - Congenital Anomaly which is not in the visible and\naccessible parts of the body",
      "type": "GENERAL",
      "subtypes": [],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Internal Congenital Anomaly - Congenital Anomaly",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 4,
          "end": 52
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "(b) External Congenital Anomaly- Congenital Anomaly which is in the visible and\naccessible parts of the body\nDef. 8. Co-payment means a cost-sharing requirement under a health insurance policy that\nprovides that the policyholder/insured will bear a specified percentage of the admissible claim\namount. A co-payment does not reduce the Sum Insured.\nDef. 9. Cumulative Bonus means any increase in the Sum Insured granted by the insurer without\nan associated increase in premium.\nDef. 10. Critical Illness means Cancer of specified severity, Open Chest CABG, First Heart Attack of\nspecified severity, Kidney Failure requiring regular dialysis, Major Organ/Bone Marrow\nTransplant, Multiple Sclerosis with Persisting Symptoms, Permanent Paralysis of Limbs, Stroke\nresulting in Permanent Symptoms as defined below only:\ni) Cancer of specified severity:\nA malignant tumour characterised by the uncontrolled growth & spread of malignant",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "External Congenital Anomaly- Congenital Anomaly",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 4,
          "end": 51
        },
        {
          "text": "8",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 114,
          "end": 115
        },
        {
          "text": "9",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 353,
          "end": 354
        },
        {
          "text": "the Sum Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 395,
          "end": 410
        },
        {
          "text": "10",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 482,
          "end": 484
        },
        {
          "text": "CABG",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 550,
          "end": 554
        },
        {
          "text": "First",
          "type": "ORDINAL",
          "start": 556,
          "end": 561
        },
        {
          "text": "Kidney Failure",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 598,
          "end": 612
        },
        {
          "text": "Bone Marrow\nTransplant, Multiple Sclerosis with Persisting Symptoms, Permanent Paralysis of Limbs",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 653,
          "end": 750
        },
        {
          "text": "Permanent Symptoms",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 772,
          "end": 790
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "i) Cancer of specified severity:\nA malignant tumour characterised by the uncontrolled growth & spread of malignant\ncells with invasion & destruction of normal tissues. This diagnosis must be supported\nby histological evidence of malignancy & confirmed by a pathologist.\nThe term cancer includes leukemia, lymphoma and sarcoma.\nThe following are excluded:\n Tumours showing the malignant changes of carcinoma in situ & tumours\nwhich are histologically described as pre-malignant or non-invasive, including\nbut not limited to: Carcinoma in situ of breasts, Cervical dysplasia CIN-1, CIN -\n2 & CIN-3.\n Any skin cancer other than invasive malignant melanoma\n All tumours of the prostate unless histologically classified as having a Gleason\nscore greater than 6 or having progressed to at least clinical TNM classification\nT2N0M0.........\n Papillary micro - carcinoma of the thyroid less than 1 cm in diameter\n Chronic lymphocyctic leukaemia less than RAI stage 3\n Microcarcinoma of the bladder",
      "type": "EXCLUSION",
      "subtypes": [
        "EXCLUSION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "CIN-1",
          "type": "WORK_OF_ART",
          "start": 574,
          "end": 579
        },
        {
          "text": "CIN",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 581,
          "end": 584
        },
        {
          "text": "2 & CIN-3",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 587,
          "end": 596
        },
        {
          "text": "Gleason",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 730,
          "end": 737
        },
        {
          "text": "TNM",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 801,
          "end": 804
        },
        {
          "text": "Papillary",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 838,
          "end": 847
        },
        {
          "text": "less than 1 cm",
          "type": "QUANTITY",
          "start": 881,
          "end": 895
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 961,
          "end": 962
        },
        {
          "text": "Microcarcinoma",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 965,
          "end": 979
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": " Chronic lymphocyctic leukaemia less than RAI stage 3\n Microcarcinoma of the bladder\n All tumours in the presence of HIV infection.\nii) Open Chest CABG:\nThe actual undergoing of open chest surgery for the correction of one or more\ncoronary arteries, which is/are narrowed or blocked, by coronary artery bypass graft\n(CABG). The Diagnosis must be supported by coronary angiography and realisation of\nthe surgery has to be confirmed by a specialist Medical Practitioner\nThe following are excluded:\n Angioplasty and / or Any other intra-arterial procedures\n Any Key-hole surgery or laser surgery\niii) First Heart Attack of Specified Severity:\nHDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited. IRDAI Reg. No.146. CIN: U66030MH2007PLC177117. Registered &\nCorporate Office: 1st Floor, HDFC House, 165-166 Backbay Reclamation, H. T. Parekh Marg, Churchgate, Mumbai – 400\n020. Trade Logo displayed above belongs to HDFC Ltd and ERGO International AG and used by the Company under",
      "type": "EXCLUSION",
      "subtypes": [
        "EXCLUSION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "3",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 53,
          "end": 54
        },
        {
          "text": "Microcarcinoma",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 57,
          "end": 71
        },
        {
          "text": "one",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 222,
          "end": 225
        },
        {
          "text": "CABG",
          "type": "LAW",
          "start": 320,
          "end": 324
        },
        {
          "text": "Medical Practitioner",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 450,
          "end": 470
        },
        {
          "text": "Angioplasty",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 501,
          "end": 512
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 645,
          "end": 688
        },
        {
          "text": "IRDAI Reg",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 690,
          "end": 699
        },
        {
          "text": "CIN",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 709,
          "end": 712
        },
        {
          "text": "1st Floor",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 768,
          "end": 777
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC House",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 779,
          "end": 789
        },
        {
          "text": "165",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 791,
          "end": 794
        },
        {
          "text": "H. T. Parekh Marg",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 820,
          "end": 837
        },
        {
          "text": "Churchgate",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 839,
          "end": 849
        },
        {
          "text": "Mumbai",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 851,
          "end": 857
        },
        {
          "text": "400",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 860,
          "end": 863
        },
        {
          "text": "020",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 864,
          "end": 867
        },
        {
          "text": "Trade Logo",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 869,
          "end": 879
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC Ltd",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 907,
          "end": 915
        },
        {
          "text": "ERGO International AG",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 920,
          "end": 941
        },
        {
          "text": "Company",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 958,
          "end": 965
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "020. Trade Logo displayed above belongs to HDFC Ltd and ERGO International AG and used by the Company under\nlicense. Easy Health UIN: HDFHLIP23024V072223\n2 | P age\nHDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited\nThe first occurrence of myocardial infarction which means the death of a portion of the\nheart muscle as a result of inadequate blood supply to the relevant area.\nThe diagnosis for this will be evidenced by all of the following criteria:\n A history of typical clinical symptoms consistent with the diagnosis of Acute\nMyocardial Infarction (for e.g. typical chest pain).\n New characteristic electrocardiogram changes.\n Elevation of infarction specific enzymes, Troponins or other specific\nbiochemical markers.\nThe following are excluded:\n Non-ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction (NSTEMI) with elevation of\nTroponin I or T.\n Other acute Coronary Syndromes.\n Any type of angina pectoris\niv) Kidney Failure requiring Regular Dialysis:",
      "type": "EXCLUSION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "EXCLUSION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "020",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 3
        },
        {
          "text": "Trade Logo",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 5,
          "end": 15
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC Ltd",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 43,
          "end": 51
        },
        {
          "text": "ERGO International AG",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 56,
          "end": 77
        },
        {
          "text": "Company",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 94,
          "end": 101
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 154,
          "end": 155
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 164,
          "end": 207
        },
        {
          "text": "first",
          "type": "ORDINAL",
          "start": 212,
          "end": 217
        },
        {
          "text": "Acute\nMyocardial Infarction",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 519,
          "end": 546
        },
        {
          "text": "Troponins",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 670,
          "end": 679
        },
        {
          "text": "Non-ST",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 749,
          "end": 755
        },
        {
          "text": "NSTEMI",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 797,
          "end": 803
        },
        {
          "text": "Troponin I or",
          "type": "WORK_OF_ART",
          "start": 823,
          "end": 836
        },
        {
          "text": "Regular Dialysis",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 933,
          "end": 949
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "Troponin I or T.\n Other acute Coronary Syndromes.\n Any type of angina pectoris\niv) Kidney Failure requiring Regular Dialysis:\nEnd stage renal disease presented as chronic irreversible failure of both kidneys to\nfunction, as a result of which either regular renal dialysis (haemodialysis or peritoneal\ndialysis) is instituted or renal transplantation is carried out.\nThe diagnosis has to be confirmed by a specialist Medical Practitioner\nv) Major Organ/ Bone Marrow Transplant:\nThe actual undergoing of a transplant of:\n One of the following human organs - heart, lung, liver, pancreas, kidney, that\nresulted from irreversible end-stage failure of the relevant organ or;\n Human bone marrow using hematopoietic stem cells.\nThe undergoing of a transplant must be confirmed by specialist medical practitioner.\nThe following are excluded:\n Other Stem-cell transplants\n Where only islets of Langerhans are transplanted\nvi) Multiple Sclerosis with Persisting Symptoms:",
      "type": "EXCLUSION",
      "subtypes": [
        "EXCLUSION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Troponin",
          "type": "LOC",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 8
        },
        {
          "text": "Regular Dialysis",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 110,
          "end": 126
        },
        {
          "text": "Medical",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 418,
          "end": 425
        },
        {
          "text": "One",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 523,
          "end": 526
        },
        {
          "text": "Langerhans",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 891,
          "end": 901
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": " Other Stem-cell transplants\n Where only islets of Langerhans are transplanted\nvi) Multiple Sclerosis with Persisting Symptoms:\nThe definite occurrence of Multiple Sclerosis.The diagnosis must be supported by all of\nthe following:\n Investigation including typical MRI and CSF findings, which unequivocally\nconfirm the diagnosis to be multiple Sclerosis.\n There must be current clinical impairment of motor or sensory function, which\nmust have persisted for a continuous period of at least 6 months.\n Well documented clinical history of exacerbations and remissions of said\nsymptoms or neurological deficits with at least two clinically documented\nepisodes at least 1 month apart.\nExcluded is:\n Other causes of neurological damage such as SLE and HIV are excluded\nvii) Permanent Paralysis of Limbs:\nTotal and irreversible loss of use of two or more limbs as a result of injury or disease of\nthe brain or spinal cord. A specialist Medical Practitioner (Physician / Neurologist) must",
      "type": "EXCLUSION",
      "subtypes": [
        "EXCLUSION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Langerhans",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 53,
          "end": 63
        },
        {
          "text": "Multiple Sclerosis",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 157,
          "end": 175
        },
        {
          "text": "CSF",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 275,
          "end": 278
        },
        {
          "text": "at least 6 months",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 484,
          "end": 501
        },
        {
          "text": "at least two",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 617,
          "end": 629
        },
        {
          "text": "at least 1 month",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 661,
          "end": 677
        },
        {
          "text": "SLE",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 744,
          "end": 747
        },
        {
          "text": "two",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 842,
          "end": 845
        },
        {
          "text": "Medical Practitioner (Physician / Neurologist",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 935,
          "end": 980
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "the brain or spinal cord. A specialist Medical Practitioner (Physician / Neurologist) must\nbe of the opinion that paralysis will be permanent with no hope of recovery and must\nbe present for more than 3 months. .\nviii) Stroke resulting in Permanent Symptoms:\nAny cerebrovascular incident producing permanent neurological sequelae. This\nincludes infarction of brain tissue, thrombosis in an intra-cranial vessel, haemorrhage\nand embolisation from an extracranial source.\nHDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited. IRDAI Reg. No.146. CIN: U66030MH2007PLC177117. Registered &\nCorporate Office: 1st Floor, HDFC House, 165-166 Backbay Reclamation, H. T. Parekh Marg, Churchgate, Mumbai – 400\n020. Trade Logo displayed above belongs to HDFC Ltd and ERGO International AG and used by the Company under\nlicense. Easy Health UIN: HDFHLIP23024V072223\n3 | P age\nHDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited\nThe diagnosis has to be confirmed by a specialist Medical Practitioner and evidenced",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Medical Practitioner (Physician / Neurologist",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 39,
          "end": 84
        },
        {
          "text": "more than 3 months",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 191,
          "end": 209
        },
        {
          "text": "Permanent Symptoms",
          "type": "FAC",
          "start": 239,
          "end": 257
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 470,
          "end": 513
        },
        {
          "text": "IRDAI Reg",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 515,
          "end": 524
        },
        {
          "text": "CIN",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 534,
          "end": 537
        },
        {
          "text": "1st Floor",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 593,
          "end": 602
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC House",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 604,
          "end": 614
        },
        {
          "text": "165",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 616,
          "end": 619
        },
        {
          "text": "H. T. Parekh Marg",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 645,
          "end": 662
        },
        {
          "text": "Churchgate",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 664,
          "end": 674
        },
        {
          "text": "Mumbai",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 676,
          "end": 682
        },
        {
          "text": "400",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 685,
          "end": 688
        },
        {
          "text": "020",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 689,
          "end": 692
        },
        {
          "text": "Trade Logo",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 694,
          "end": 704
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC Ltd",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 732,
          "end": 740
        },
        {
          "text": "ERGO International AG",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 745,
          "end": 766
        },
        {
          "text": "Company",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 783,
          "end": 790
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 843,
          "end": 844
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 853,
          "end": 896
        },
        {
          "text": "Medical Practitioner",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 947,
          "end": 967
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.0
    },
    {
      "text": "3 | P age\nHDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited\nThe diagnosis has to be confirmed by a specialist Medical Practitioner and evidenced\nby typical clinical symptoms as well as typical findings in CT Scan or MRI of the brain.\nEvidence of permanent neurological deficit lasting for atleast 3 months has to be\nproduced.\nThe following are excluded:\n Transient ischemic attacks (TIA)\n Traumatic injury of the brain\n Vascular diseases affecting only the eye or optic nerve or vestibular functions\nDef. 11. Day Care centre means any institution established for day care treatment of illness and/or\ninjuries or a medical setup within a hospital and which has been registered with the local\nauthorities, wherever applicable, and is under the supervision of a registered and qualified\nmedical practitioner AND must comply with all minimum criteria as under—\n-has qualified nursing staff under its employment;\n-has qualified medical practitioner/s in charge;",
      "type": "EXCLUSION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "EXCLUSION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "3",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 1
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 10,
          "end": 53
        },
        {
          "text": "Medical Practitioner",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 104,
          "end": 124
        },
        {
          "text": "CT Scan",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 199,
          "end": 206
        },
        {
          "text": "atleast 3 months",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 283,
          "end": 299
        },
        {
          "text": "Traumatic",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 385,
          "end": 394
        },
        {
          "text": "Vascular",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 417,
          "end": 425
        },
        {
          "text": "11",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 502,
          "end": 504
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "-has qualified nursing staff under its employment;\n-has qualified medical practitioner/s in charge;\n-has a fully equipped operation theatre of its own where surgical procedures are carried out;\n-maintains daily records of patients and will make these accessible to the insurance company’s\nauthorized personnel\nDef. 12. Day Care Procedures means those medical treatment, and/or surgical procedure\ni. which is undertaken under General or Local Anaesthesia in a Hospital/day care centre\nin less than 24 hours because of technological advancement,\nii. which would have otherwise required a Hospitalisation of more than 24 hours.\nTreatment normally taken on an Out-patient basis is not included in the scope of this definition\nDef. 13. Deductible means a cost-sharing requirement under a health insurance policy that provides\nthat the insurer will not be liable for a specified rupee amount in case of indemnity policies and",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "daily",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 205,
          "end": 210
        },
        {
          "text": "12",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 315,
          "end": 317
        },
        {
          "text": "less than 24 hours",
          "type": "TIME",
          "start": 487,
          "end": 505
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospitalisation",
          "type": "EVENT",
          "start": 586,
          "end": 601
        },
        {
          "text": "24 hours",
          "type": "TIME",
          "start": 615,
          "end": 623
        },
        {
          "text": "13",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 727,
          "end": 729
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "that the insurer will not be liable for a specified rupee amount in case of indemnity policies and\nfor a specified number of days/hours in case of hospital cash policies which will apply before\nany benefits are payable by the insurer. A deductible does not reduce the Sum Insured.\nDef. 14. Dental treatment means a treatment related to teeth or structures supporting teeth\nincluding examinations, filings (where appropriate), crowns, extractions and surgery.\nDef. 15. Domiciliary Hospitalisation means medical treatment for an illness/disease/injury which in\nthe normal course would require a care and treatment at a Hospital but is actually taken while\nconfined at home under any of the following circumstances:",
      "type": "COVERAGE",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "COVERAGE"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "days/hours",
          "type": "TIME",
          "start": 125,
          "end": 135
        },
        {
          "text": "14",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 286,
          "end": 288
        },
        {
          "text": "15",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 464,
          "end": 466
        },
        {
          "text": "Domiciliary Hospitalisation",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 468,
          "end": 495
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.6666666666666666
    },
    {
      "text": "- The condition of the patient is such that he/she is not in a condition to be removed to a\nhospital, or",
      "type": "GENERAL",
      "subtypes": [],
      "entities": [],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "- The patient takes treatment at home on account of non-availability of a room in a\nhospital\nDef. 16. Disclosure of information norm means the policy shall be void and all premiums paid hereon\nshall be forfeited to the Company, in the event of misrepresentation, mis-description or non-\ndisclosure of any material fact.\nDef. 17. Emergency Care means management for a severe illness or injury which results in symptoms\nwhich occur suddenly and unexpectedly, and requires immediate care by a medical\npractitioner to prevent death or serious long term impairment of the insured person’s health.\nDef. 18. Grace Period means the specified period of time immediately following the premium due date\nduring which a payment can be made to renew or continue a Policy in force without loss of\ncontinuity benefits such as waiting periods and coverage of Pre-Existing Diseases. Coverage is\nnot available for the period for which no premium is received.",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "16",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 98,
          "end": 100
        },
        {
          "text": "Company",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 219,
          "end": 226
        },
        {
          "text": "17",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 325,
          "end": 327
        },
        {
          "text": "18",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 597,
          "end": 599
        },
        {
          "text": "Grace Period",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 601,
          "end": 613
        },
        {
          "text": "Pre-Existing Diseases",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 842,
          "end": 863
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "not available for the period for which no premium is received.\nDef. 19. Hospital means any institution established for in-patient care and day care treatment of\nillness and/or injuries and which has been registered as a hospital with the local authorities\nHDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited. IRDAI Reg. No.146. CIN: U66030MH2007PLC177117. Registered &\nCorporate Office: 1st Floor, HDFC House, 165-166 Backbay Reclamation, H. T. Parekh Marg, Churchgate, Mumbai – 400\n020. Trade Logo displayed above belongs to HDFC Ltd and ERGO International AG and used by the Company under\nlicense. Easy Health UIN: HDFHLIP23024V072223\n4 | P age\nHDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited\nunder the Clinical Establishments (Registration and Regulation) Act, 2010 or under the\nenactments specified under the Schedule of Section 56(1) of the said Act OR complies with all\nminimum criteria as under:\n has qualified nursing staff under its employment round the clock,",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "19",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 68,
          "end": 70
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 256,
          "end": 299
        },
        {
          "text": "IRDAI Reg",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 301,
          "end": 310
        },
        {
          "text": "CIN",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 320,
          "end": 323
        },
        {
          "text": "1st Floor",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 379,
          "end": 388
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC House",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 390,
          "end": 400
        },
        {
          "text": "165",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 402,
          "end": 405
        },
        {
          "text": "H. T. Parekh Marg",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 431,
          "end": 448
        },
        {
          "text": "Churchgate",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 450,
          "end": 460
        },
        {
          "text": "Mumbai",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 462,
          "end": 468
        },
        {
          "text": "400",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 471,
          "end": 474
        },
        {
          "text": "020",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 475,
          "end": 478
        },
        {
          "text": "Trade Logo",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 480,
          "end": 490
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC Ltd",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 518,
          "end": 526
        },
        {
          "text": "ERGO International AG",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 531,
          "end": 552
        },
        {
          "text": "Company",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 569,
          "end": 576
        },
        {
          "text": "4",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 629,
          "end": 630
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 639,
          "end": 682
        },
        {
          "text": "the Clinical Establishments (Registration and Regulation) Act",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 689,
          "end": 750
        },
        {
          "text": "2010",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 752,
          "end": 756
        },
        {
          "text": "the Schedule of Section 56(1",
          "type": "LAW",
          "start": 797,
          "end": 825
        },
        {
          "text": "Act",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 839,
          "end": 842
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "minimum criteria as under:\n has qualified nursing staff under its employment round the clock,\n has at least 10 in-patient beds, in those towns having a population of less than 10,00,000\nand 15 in-patient beds in all other places,\n has qualified Medical Practitioner(s) in charge round the clock,\n has a fully equipped operation theatre of its own where surgical procedures are carried out,\n maintains daily records of patients and will make these accessible to the insurance\ncompany’s authorized personnel.\nDef. 20. Hospitalisation or Hospitalised means admission in a Hospital for a minimum of 24\nconsecutive ‘In-patient Care’ hours except for specified procedures / treatments, where such\nadmission could be for a period of less than 24 consecutive hours.\nDef. 21. Illness means a sickness or a disease or pathological condition leading to the\nimpairment of normal physiological function which manifests itself during the Policy Period and\nrequires medical treatment",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "at least 10",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 101,
          "end": 112
        },
        {
          "text": "less than 10,00,000",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 168,
          "end": 187
        },
        {
          "text": "15",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 192,
          "end": 194
        },
        {
          "text": "Practitioner(s",
          "type": "NORP",
          "start": 256,
          "end": 270
        },
        {
          "text": "daily",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 406,
          "end": 411
        },
        {
          "text": "20.",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 517,
          "end": 520
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospitalised",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 540,
          "end": 552
        },
        {
          "text": "24",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 600,
          "end": 602
        },
        {
          "text": "less than",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 731,
          "end": 740
        },
        {
          "text": "24 consecutive hours",
          "type": "TIME",
          "start": 741,
          "end": 761
        },
        {
          "text": "21",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 768,
          "end": 770
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Period",
          "type": "LAW",
          "start": 925,
          "end": 942
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "impairment of normal physiological function which manifests itself during the Policy Period and\nrequires medical treatment\na) Acute Condition- Acute condition is a disease, illness or injury that is likely to respond quickly to\ntreatment which aims to return the person to his or her state of health immediately before\nsuffering the disease/illness/injury which leads to full recovery.\nb) Chronic Condition- A chronic condition is defined as disease, illness, or injury that has one or\nmore o f the following characteristics:",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "the Policy Period",
          "type": "LAW",
          "start": 74,
          "end": 91
        },
        {
          "text": "one",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 479,
          "end": 482
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "- it needs ongoing or long-term monitoring through consultations, examinations, check-ups, and\n/ or tests\n—it needs ongoing or long-term control or relief of symptoms\n— it requires your rehabilitation or for you to be specially trained to cope with it\n—it continues indefinitely\n—it recurs or is likely to recur\nDef. 22. Injury means accidental physical bodily harm excluding illness or disease solely and directly\ncaused by external, violent and visible and evident means which is verified and certified by a\nMedical Practitioner.\nDef. 23. In-patient Care means treatment for which the Insured Person has to stay in a Hospital for\nmore than 24 hours for a covered event.\nDef. 24. Maternity expenses means\ni. medical treatment expenses traceable to childbirth (including complicated deliveries\nand caesarean sections during hospitalization);\nii. expenses towards lawful medical termination of pregnancy during the Policy Period.",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION",
        "COVERAGE"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "22",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 317,
          "end": 319
        },
        {
          "text": "23",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 537,
          "end": 539
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 583,
          "end": 601
        },
        {
          "text": "more than 24 hours",
          "type": "TIME",
          "start": 632,
          "end": 650
        },
        {
          "text": "24",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 677,
          "end": 679
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Period",
          "type": "LAW",
          "start": 910,
          "end": 927
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "and caesarean sections during hospitalization);\nii. expenses towards lawful medical termination of pregnancy during the Policy Period.\nDef. 25. Medical Advise means any consultation or advise from a Medical Practitioner including the\nissuance of any prescription or follow up prescription.\nDef. 26. Medical Expenses means those expenses that an Insured Person has necessarily and actually\nincurred for medical treatment on account of illness or Accident on the advice of a Medical\nPractitioner, as long as these are no more than would have been payable if the Insured Person\nhad not been insured and no more than other Hospitals or doctors in the same locality would\nhave charged for the same medical treatment.\nDef. 27. Medically Necessary means any treatment, test, medication, or stay in Hospital or part of\nstay in Hospital which\n Is required for the medical management of the Illness or injury suffered by the Insured\nPerson;",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION",
        "COVERAGE"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "the Policy Period",
          "type": "LAW",
          "start": 116,
          "end": 133
        },
        {
          "text": "25",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 140,
          "end": 142
        },
        {
          "text": "Medical Practitioner",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 199,
          "end": 219
        },
        {
          "text": "26",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 295,
          "end": 297
        },
        {
          "text": "an Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 342,
          "end": 359
        },
        {
          "text": "Accident",
          "type": "LOC",
          "start": 445,
          "end": 453
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 556,
          "end": 574
        },
        {
          "text": "27",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 717,
          "end": 719
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 791,
          "end": 799
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 819,
          "end": 827
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured\nPerson",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 912,
          "end": 930
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "stay in Hospital which\n Is required for the medical management of the Illness or injury suffered by the Insured\nPerson;\nHDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited. IRDAI Reg. No.146. CIN: U66030MH2007PLC177117. Registered &\nCorporate Office: 1st Floor, HDFC House, 165-166 Backbay Reclamation, H. T. Parekh Marg, Churchgate, Mumbai – 400\n020. Trade Logo displayed above belongs to HDFC Ltd and ERGO International AG and used by the Company under\nlicense. Easy Health UIN: HDFHLIP23024V072223\n5 | P age\nHDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited\n Must not exceed the level of care necessary to provide safe, adequate and appropriate\nmedical care in scope, duration or intensity.\n Must have been prescribed by a Medical Practitioner.\n Must conform to the professional standards widely accepted in international medical\npractice or by the medical community in India.\nDef. 28. Medical Practitioner means a person who holds a valid registration from the medical",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Hospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 8,
          "end": 16
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured\nPerson",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 101,
          "end": 119
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 121,
          "end": 164
        },
        {
          "text": "IRDAI Reg",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 166,
          "end": 175
        },
        {
          "text": "CIN",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 185,
          "end": 188
        },
        {
          "text": "1st Floor",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 244,
          "end": 253
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC House",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 255,
          "end": 265
        },
        {
          "text": "165",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 267,
          "end": 270
        },
        {
          "text": "H. T. Parekh Marg",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 296,
          "end": 313
        },
        {
          "text": "Churchgate",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 315,
          "end": 325
        },
        {
          "text": "Mumbai",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 327,
          "end": 333
        },
        {
          "text": "400",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 336,
          "end": 339
        },
        {
          "text": "020",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 340,
          "end": 343
        },
        {
          "text": "Trade Logo",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 345,
          "end": 355
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC Ltd",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 383,
          "end": 391
        },
        {
          "text": "ERGO International AG",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 396,
          "end": 417
        },
        {
          "text": "Company",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 434,
          "end": 441
        },
        {
          "text": "5",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 494,
          "end": 495
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 504,
          "end": 547
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 863,
          "end": 868
        },
        {
          "text": "28",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 875,
          "end": 877
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.0
    },
    {
      "text": "practice or by the medical community in India.\nDef. 28. Medical Practitioner means a person who holds a valid registration from the medical\ncouncil of any state or medical council of India or council for Indian medicine or for homeopathy\nset up by the government of India or a state government and is thereby entitled to practice\nmedicine within its jurisdiction; and is acting within the scope and jurisdiction of license.\nDef. 29. Migration means the right accorded to individual health insurance policyholders (including\nall members under family cover and members of group health insurance policy) to transfer the\ncredits gained for pre-existing conditions and time-bound exclusions, with the same insurer.\nDef. 30. Network Provider means Hospital enlisted by an insurer or a TPA or jointly by an insurer and\na TPA to provide medical services to an insured by a cashless facility.\nDef. 31. New Born Baby means baby born during the Policy Period and is aged up to 90 days.",
      "type": "LIMITATION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "LIMITATION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 40,
          "end": 45
        },
        {
          "text": "28",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 52,
          "end": 54
        },
        {
          "text": "council of India",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 172,
          "end": 188
        },
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "type": "NORP",
          "start": 204,
          "end": 210
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 266,
          "end": 271
        },
        {
          "text": "29",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 429,
          "end": 431
        },
        {
          "text": "30",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 715,
          "end": 717
        },
        {
          "text": "Network Provider means Hospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 719,
          "end": 750
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Period",
          "type": "LAW",
          "start": 930,
          "end": 947
        },
        {
          "text": "up to 90 days",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 960,
          "end": 973
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.0
    },
    {
      "text": "Def. 31. New Born Baby means baby born during the Policy Period and is aged up to 90 days.\nDef. 32. Non Network Provider means any Hospital, day care centre or other provider that is not part\nof the Network\nDef. 33. Notification of Claim means the process of intimating a claim to the insurer or TPA through\nany of the recognized modes of communication.\nDef. 34. OPD treatment means the one in which the Insured visits a clinic / hospital or associated\nfacility like a consultation room for diagnosis and treatment based on the advice of a Medical\nPractitioner. The Insured is not admitted as a day care or in-patient\nDef. 35. Portability means the right accorded to individual health insurance policyholders (including\nall members under family cover) to transfer the credits gained for pre-existing conditions and\ntime-bound exclusions, from one insurer to another insurer.\nDef. 36. Pre-existing Disease means any condition, ailment, injury or disease:",
      "type": "LIMITATION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "LIMITATION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "the Policy Period",
          "type": "LAW",
          "start": 46,
          "end": 63
        },
        {
          "text": "up to 90 days",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 76,
          "end": 89
        },
        {
          "text": "32",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 96,
          "end": 98
        },
        {
          "text": "Non Network Provider",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 100,
          "end": 120
        },
        {
          "text": "the Network\nDef",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 195,
          "end": 210
        },
        {
          "text": "33",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 212,
          "end": 214
        },
        {
          "text": "34",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 359,
          "end": 361
        },
        {
          "text": "OPD",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 363,
          "end": 366
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 566,
          "end": 573
        },
        {
          "text": "35",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 623,
          "end": 625
        },
        {
          "text": "one",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 843,
          "end": 846
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.0
    },
    {
      "text": "time-bound exclusions, from one insurer to another insurer.\nDef. 36. Pre-existing Disease means any condition, ailment, injury or disease:\na) That is/are diagnosed by a physician within 48 months prior to the effective date of the\npolicy issued by the insurer or its reinstatement or\nb) For which medical advice or treatment was recommended by, or received from, a\nphysician within 48 months prior to the effective date of the policy issued by the\ninsurer or its reinstatement.\nDef. 37. Pre- Hospitalisation Medical Expenses means the medical expenses incurred during\npredefined number of days preceding the hospitalization of the Insured Person, provided that:\ni. Such Medical Expenses are incurred for the same condition for which the Insured\nPerson’s Hospitalisation was required, and\nii. The In-patient Hospitalization claim for such Hospitalization is admissible by the\nInsurance Company\nDef. 38. Post-Hospitalisation Medical Expenses means medical expenses incurred during predefined",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "one",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 28,
          "end": 31
        },
        {
          "text": "48 months",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 186,
          "end": 195
        },
        {
          "text": "48 months",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 382,
          "end": 391
        },
        {
          "text": "37",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 483,
          "end": 485
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospitalisation Medical Expenses",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 492,
          "end": 524
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 627,
          "end": 645
        },
        {
          "text": "the Insured\nPerson’s Hospitalisation",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 733,
          "end": 769
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospitalization",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 807,
          "end": 822
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospitalization",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 838,
          "end": 853
        },
        {
          "text": "the\nInsurance Company\nDef",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 871,
          "end": 896
        },
        {
          "text": "38",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 898,
          "end": 900
        },
        {
          "text": "Post-Hospitalisation Medical Expenses means medical",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 902,
          "end": 953
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "Insurance Company\nDef. 38. Post-Hospitalisation Medical Expenses means medical expenses incurred during predefined\nnumber of days immediately after the insured person is discharged from the hospital provided\nthat:\ni. Such Medical Expenses are for the same condition for which the insured person’s\nhospitalization was required, and\nii. The inpatient hospitalization claim for such hospitalization is admissible by the insurance\ncompany\nHDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited. IRDAI Reg. No.146. CIN: U66030MH2007PLC177117. Registered &\nCorporate Office: 1st Floor, HDFC House, 165-166 Backbay Reclamation, H. T. Parekh Marg, Churchgate, Mumbai – 400\n020. Trade Logo displayed above belongs to HDFC Ltd and ERGO International AG and used by the Company under\nlicense. Easy Health UIN: HDFHLIP23024V072223\n6 | P age\nHDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited\nDef. 39. Qualified Nurse is a person who holds a valid registration from the nursing council of India",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Insurance Company\nDef",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 21
        },
        {
          "text": "38",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 23,
          "end": 25
        },
        {
          "text": "Post-Hospitalisation Medical Expenses means medical",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 27,
          "end": 78
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 435,
          "end": 478
        },
        {
          "text": "IRDAI Reg",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 480,
          "end": 489
        },
        {
          "text": "CIN",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 499,
          "end": 502
        },
        {
          "text": "1st Floor",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 558,
          "end": 567
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC House",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 569,
          "end": 579
        },
        {
          "text": "165",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 581,
          "end": 584
        },
        {
          "text": "H. T. Parekh Marg",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 610,
          "end": 627
        },
        {
          "text": "Churchgate",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 629,
          "end": 639
        },
        {
          "text": "Mumbai",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 641,
          "end": 647
        },
        {
          "text": "400",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 650,
          "end": 653
        },
        {
          "text": "020",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 654,
          "end": 657
        },
        {
          "text": "Trade Logo",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 659,
          "end": 669
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC Ltd",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 697,
          "end": 705
        },
        {
          "text": "ERGO International AG",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 710,
          "end": 731
        },
        {
          "text": "Company",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 748,
          "end": 755
        },
        {
          "text": "6",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 808,
          "end": 809
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 818,
          "end": 861
        },
        {
          "text": "39",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 867,
          "end": 869
        },
        {
          "text": "Qualified Nurse",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 871,
          "end": 886
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 958,
          "end": 963
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited\nDef. 39. Qualified Nurse is a person who holds a valid registration from the nursing council of India\nor the nursing council of any state in India\nDef. 40. Reasonable & Customary Charges means the charges for services or supplies, which are the\nstandard\ncharges for a specific provider and consistent with the prevailing charges in the geographical\narea for identical or similar services, taking into account the nature of illness/ injury involved.\nDef. 41. Room Rent means the amount charged by a hospital towards room and boarding expenses\nand shall include associated medical expenses.\nDef. 42. Renewal means the terms on which the contract of insurance can be renewed on mutual\nconsent with a provision of grace period for treating the renewal continuous for the purpose of\ngaining credit for pre-existing diseases, time bound exclusions and for all waiting periods.",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited\nDef",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 47
        },
        {
          "text": "39",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 49,
          "end": 51
        },
        {
          "text": "Qualified Nurse",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 53,
          "end": 68
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 140,
          "end": 145
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 185,
          "end": 190
        },
        {
          "text": "40",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 196,
          "end": 198
        },
        {
          "text": "41",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 498,
          "end": 500
        },
        {
          "text": "42",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 638,
          "end": 640
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "gaining credit for pre-existing diseases, time bound exclusions and for all waiting periods.\nDef. 43. Surgery or Surgical Procedure means manual and/or operative procedure(s) required for\ntreatment of an Illness or injury, correction of deformities and defects, diagnosis and cure of\ndiseases, relief of suffering or prolongation of life, performed in a Hospital or day care centre by\na Medical Practitioner.\nDef. 44. Unproven/Experimental treatment means treatment including drug experimental therapy\nwhich is not based on established medical practice in India, is treatment experimental or\nunproven.\nDef. 45. Intensive Care Unit means an identified section, ward or wing of a Hospital which is under\nthe constant supervision of a dedicated Medical Practitioner(s), and which is specially equipped\nfor the continuous monitoring and treatment of patients who are in a critical condition, or\nrequire life support facilities and where the level of care and supervision is considerably more",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "43",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 98,
          "end": 100
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 354,
          "end": 362
        },
        {
          "text": "44",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 414,
          "end": 416
        },
        {
          "text": "India",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 556,
          "end": 561
        },
        {
          "text": "45",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 607,
          "end": 609
        },
        {
          "text": "Practitioner(s",
          "type": "NORP",
          "start": 750,
          "end": 764
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "require life support facilities and where the level of care and supervision is considerably more\nsophisticated and intensive than in the ordinary and other wards.\nDef. 46. ICU (Intensive Care Unit) Charges means the amount charged by a Hospital towards ICU\nexpenses which shall include the coverage for bed, general medical support services provided to\nany ICU patient including monitoring devices, critical care nursing and intensivist charges.",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "46",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 168,
          "end": 170
        },
        {
          "text": "Intensive Care Unit)",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 177,
          "end": 197
        },
        {
          "text": "ICU",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 357,
          "end": 360
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "2. Specific Definitions\nDef. 1. Adventurous/Hazardous Sports means any sport or activity involving physical exertion and skill\nin which an Insured Person participates or competes for entertainment or as part of his\nProfession whether he / she is trained or not.\nDef. 2. Age or Aged means completed years as at the Commencement Date.\nDef. 3. Alternative treatments means forms of treatments other than treatment \"Allopathy\" or\n\"modern medicine\" and includes Ayurveda, Unani, Sidha and Homeopathy in the Indian context\nDef. 4. AYUSH Treatment refers to hospitalisation treatments given under Ayurveda, Yoga and\nNaturopathy, Unani, Siddha and Homeopathy systems.\nDef. 5. Bank Rate means the rate fixed by the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) at the beginning of the\nfinancial year in which claim has fallen due.\nContribution means essentially the right of an insurer to call upon other insurers liable to the\nsame insured to share the cost of an indemnity claim on a rateable proportion of Sum Insured.",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 1
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 29,
          "end": 30
        },
        {
          "text": "2",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 267,
          "end": 268
        },
        {
          "text": "Aged",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 277,
          "end": 281
        },
        {
          "text": "years",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 298,
          "end": 303
        },
        {
          "text": "the Commencement Date",
          "type": "EVENT",
          "start": 310,
          "end": 331
        },
        {
          "text": "3.",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 338,
          "end": 340
        },
        {
          "text": "Allopathy",
          "type": "WORK_OF_ART",
          "start": 412,
          "end": 421
        },
        {
          "text": "Ayurveda, Unani, Sidha",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 457,
          "end": 479
        },
        {
          "text": "Homeopathy",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 484,
          "end": 494
        },
        {
          "text": "Indian",
          "type": "NORP",
          "start": 502,
          "end": 508
        },
        {
          "text": "4",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 522,
          "end": 523
        },
        {
          "text": "Unani",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 622,
          "end": 627
        },
        {
          "text": "Siddha",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 629,
          "end": 635
        },
        {
          "text": "Homeopathy",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 640,
          "end": 650
        },
        {
          "text": "5",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 665,
          "end": 666
        },
        {
          "text": "Bank Rate",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 668,
          "end": 677
        },
        {
          "text": "the Reserve Bank of India",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 702,
          "end": 727
        },
        {
          "text": "RBI",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 729,
          "end": 732
        },
        {
          "text": "Sum Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 982,
          "end": 993
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "same insured to share the cost of an indemnity claim on a rateable proportion of Sum Insured.\nThis clause shall not apply to any Benefit offered on fixed benefit basis.\nHDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited. IRDAI Reg. No.146. CIN: U66030MH2007PLC177117. Registered &\nCorporate Office: 1st Floor, HDFC House, 165-166 Backbay Reclamation, H. T. Parekh Marg, Churchgate, Mumbai – 400\n020. Trade Logo displayed above belongs to HDFC Ltd and ERGO International AG and used by the Company under\nlicense. Easy Health UIN: HDFHLIP23024V072223\n7 | P age\nHDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited\nDef. 6. Commencement Date means the commencement date of this Policy as specified in the\nSchedule.\nDef. 7. Dependents means only the family members listed below:\ni) Your legally married spouse as long as she continues to be married to You;\nii) Your children / Grandchildren Aged between 91 days and 25 years if they are unmarried",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION",
        "COVERAGE"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Sum Insured",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 81,
          "end": 92
        },
        {
          "text": "Benefit",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 129,
          "end": 136
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 169,
          "end": 212
        },
        {
          "text": "IRDAI Reg",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 214,
          "end": 223
        },
        {
          "text": "CIN",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 233,
          "end": 236
        },
        {
          "text": "1st Floor",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 292,
          "end": 301
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC House",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 303,
          "end": 313
        },
        {
          "text": "165",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 315,
          "end": 318
        },
        {
          "text": "H. T. Parekh Marg",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 344,
          "end": 361
        },
        {
          "text": "Churchgate",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 363,
          "end": 373
        },
        {
          "text": "Mumbai",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 375,
          "end": 381
        },
        {
          "text": "400",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 384,
          "end": 387
        },
        {
          "text": "020",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 388,
          "end": 391
        },
        {
          "text": "Trade Logo",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 393,
          "end": 403
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC Ltd",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 431,
          "end": 439
        },
        {
          "text": "ERGO International AG",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 444,
          "end": 465
        },
        {
          "text": "Company",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 482,
          "end": 489
        },
        {
          "text": "7",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 542,
          "end": 543
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 552,
          "end": 595
        },
        {
          "text": "6.",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 601,
          "end": 603
        },
        {
          "text": "between 91 days",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 875,
          "end": 890
        },
        {
          "text": "25 years",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 895,
          "end": 903
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "ii) Your children / Grandchildren Aged between 91 days and 25 years if they are unmarried\nand financially dependent with no independent source of income. Children Aged\nbetween 1 to 90 Days can be covered if Newborn Baby Benefit is added by payment of\nadditional premium subject to policy terms and conditions.\niii) Your natural parents or parents that have legally adopted You, provided that the parent was\nbelow 65 years at his initial participation in the Easy Health Policy,\niv) Your Parent -in-law as long as Your spouse continues to be married to You and were below\n65 years at his initial participation in the Easy Health Policy\nv) Your Grandparents provided that the grandparent were below 65 years at his initial\nparticipation in the Easy Health Policy,\nAll Dependent parents, Parent in laws, Grand Parents must be financially dependent on You.\nDef. 8. Dependent Child means a child (natural or legally adopted), who is unmarried, Aged between 91",
      "type": "LIMITATION",
      "subtypes": [
        "LIMITATION",
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION",
        "COVERAGE"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "between 91 days",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 39,
          "end": 54
        },
        {
          "text": "25 years",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 59,
          "end": 67
        },
        {
          "text": "between 1 to 90 Days",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 168,
          "end": 188
        },
        {
          "text": "Newborn Baby Benefit",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 207,
          "end": 227
        },
        {
          "text": "65 years",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 413,
          "end": 421
        },
        {
          "text": "the Easy Health Policy",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 454,
          "end": 476
        },
        {
          "text": "65 years",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 571,
          "end": 579
        },
        {
          "text": "the Easy Health Policy",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 612,
          "end": 634
        },
        {
          "text": "65 years",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 697,
          "end": 705
        },
        {
          "text": "the Easy Health Policy",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 738,
          "end": 760
        },
        {
          "text": "Dependent",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 766,
          "end": 775
        },
        {
          "text": "Grand Parents",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 801,
          "end": 814
        },
        {
          "text": "8.",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 858,
          "end": 860
        },
        {
          "text": "Aged",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 939,
          "end": 943
        },
        {
          "text": "91",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 952,
          "end": 954
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.0
    },
    {
      "text": "Def. 8. Dependent Child means a child (natural or legally adopted), who is unmarried, Aged between 91\ndays and 25 years, financially dependent on the primary Insured or Proposer and does not\nhave his / her independent sources of income. Children Aged between 1 to 90 Days can be\ncovered if Newborn Baby Benefit is added by payment of additional premium subject to policy\nterms and conditions.\nDef. 9. Family Floater means a Policy described as such in the Schedule where under You and Your\nDependents named in the Schedule are insured under this Policy as at the Commencement\nDate. The Sum Insured for a Family Floater means the sum shown in the Schedule which\nrepresents Our maximum liability for any and all claims made by You and/or all of Your\nDependents during the Policy Year.\nDef. 10. Insured Person means You and the persons named in the Schedule.\nDef. 11. Material Facts means all relevant information sought by the Company in the Proposal Form",
      "type": "LIMITATION",
      "subtypes": [
        "LIMITATION",
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION",
        "COVERAGE"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "8.",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 5,
          "end": 7
        },
        {
          "text": "between 91\ndays",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 91,
          "end": 106
        },
        {
          "text": "25 years",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 111,
          "end": 119
        },
        {
          "text": "Proposer",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 169,
          "end": 177
        },
        {
          "text": "between 1 to 90 Days",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 251,
          "end": 271
        },
        {
          "text": "Newborn Baby Benefit",
          "type": "PRODUCT",
          "start": 290,
          "end": 310
        },
        {
          "text": "9.",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 398,
          "end": 400
        },
        {
          "text": "Floater",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 408,
          "end": 415
        },
        {
          "text": "Schedule",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 456,
          "end": 464
        },
        {
          "text": "Schedule",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 514,
          "end": 522
        },
        {
          "text": "Policy",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 546,
          "end": 552
        },
        {
          "text": "the Commencement\nDate",
          "type": "EVENT",
          "start": 559,
          "end": 580
        },
        {
          "text": "Floater",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 611,
          "end": 618
        },
        {
          "text": "Schedule",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 646,
          "end": 654
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Year",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 766,
          "end": 781
        },
        {
          "text": "10",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 788,
          "end": 790
        },
        {
          "text": "Schedule",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 846,
          "end": 854
        },
        {
          "text": "11",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 861,
          "end": 863
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "Def. 11. Material Facts means all relevant information sought by the Company in the Proposal Form\nand other connected documents to enable it to take informed decision in the context of\nunderwriting the risk.\nDef. 12. Policy means Your statements in the proposal form (which are the basis of this Policy), this\npolicy wording (including endorsements, if any), Annexure 1 and the Schedule (as the same may\nbe amended from time to time).\nDef. 13. Policy Period means the period between the Commencement Date and the Expiry Date\nspecified in the Schedule.\nDef. 14. Policy Year means a year following the Commencement Date and its subsequent annual\nanniversary.\nDef. 15. Shared accommodation means a Hospital room with two or more patient beds.\nDef. 16. Single occupancy or any higher accommodation type means a Hospital room with only one\npatient bed.\nDef. 17. Sum Insured means the sum shown in the Schedule which represents Our maximum",
      "type": "LIMITATION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "CONDITION",
        "LIMITATION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "11",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 5,
          "end": 7
        },
        {
          "text": "12",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 213,
          "end": 215
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 368,
          "end": 369
        },
        {
          "text": "13",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 440,
          "end": 442
        },
        {
          "text": "the Commencement Date",
          "type": "EVENT",
          "start": 483,
          "end": 504
        },
        {
          "text": "Schedule",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 542,
          "end": 550
        },
        {
          "text": "14",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 557,
          "end": 559
        },
        {
          "text": "Policy Year",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 561,
          "end": 572
        },
        {
          "text": "a year",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 579,
          "end": 585
        },
        {
          "text": "the Commencement Date",
          "type": "EVENT",
          "start": 596,
          "end": 617
        },
        {
          "text": "annual",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 637,
          "end": 643
        },
        {
          "text": "15",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 662,
          "end": 664
        },
        {
          "text": "two",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 714,
          "end": 717
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 745,
          "end": 747
        },
        {
          "text": "only one",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 826,
          "end": 834
        },
        {
          "text": "17",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 853,
          "end": 855
        },
        {
          "text": "Schedule",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 896,
          "end": 904
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.3333333333333333
    },
    {
      "text": "patient bed.\nDef. 17. Sum Insured means the sum shown in the Schedule which represents Our maximum\nliability for each Insured Person for any and all benefits claimed for during the Policy Year.\nDef. 18. TPA means the third party administrator that We appoint from time to time as specified in\nthe Schedule.\nHDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited. IRDAI Reg. No.146. CIN: U66030MH2007PLC177117. Registered &\nCorporate Office: 1st Floor, HDFC House, 165-166 Backbay Reclamation, H. T. Parekh Marg, Churchgate, Mumbai – 400\n020. Trade Logo displayed above belongs to HDFC Ltd and ERGO International AG and used by the Company under\nlicense. Easy Health UIN: HDFHLIP23024V072223\n8 | P age\nHDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited\nDef. 19. We/Our/Us means the HDFC ERGO General Insurance Limited.\nDef. 20. You/Your/Policyholder means the person named in the Schedule who has concluded this\nPolicy with Us.\nSection B. Benefits",
      "type": "LIMITATION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION",
        "LIMITATION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "17",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 18,
          "end": 20
        },
        {
          "text": "Schedule",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 61,
          "end": 69
        },
        {
          "text": "Insured Person",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 118,
          "end": 132
        },
        {
          "text": "the Policy Year",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 177,
          "end": 192
        },
        {
          "text": "18",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 199,
          "end": 201
        },
        {
          "text": "third",
          "type": "ORDINAL",
          "start": 217,
          "end": 222
        },
        {
          "text": "Schedule",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 297,
          "end": 305
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 307,
          "end": 350
        },
        {
          "text": "IRDAI Reg",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 352,
          "end": 361
        },
        {
          "text": "CIN",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 371,
          "end": 374
        },
        {
          "text": "1st Floor",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 430,
          "end": 439
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC House",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 441,
          "end": 451
        },
        {
          "text": "165",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 453,
          "end": 456
        },
        {
          "text": "H. T. Parekh Marg",
          "type": "PERSON",
          "start": 482,
          "end": 499
        },
        {
          "text": "Churchgate",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 501,
          "end": 511
        },
        {
          "text": "Mumbai",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 513,
          "end": 519
        },
        {
          "text": "400",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 522,
          "end": 525
        },
        {
          "text": "020",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 526,
          "end": 529
        },
        {
          "text": "Trade Logo",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 531,
          "end": 541
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC Ltd",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 569,
          "end": 577
        },
        {
          "text": "ERGO International AG",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 582,
          "end": 603
        },
        {
          "text": "Company",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 620,
          "end": 627
        },
        {
          "text": "8",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 680,
          "end": 681
        },
        {
          "text": "HDFC ERGO General Insurance Company Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 690,
          "end": 733
        },
        {
          "text": "19",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 739,
          "end": 741
        },
        {
          "text": "the HDFC ERGO General Insurance Limited",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 759,
          "end": 798
        },
        {
          "text": "20",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 805,
          "end": 807
        },
        {
          "text": "Schedule",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 861,
          "end": 869
        },
        {
          "text": "Us",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 905,
          "end": 907
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.6666666666666666
    },
    {
      "text": "Def. 20. You/Your/Policyholder means the person named in the Schedule who has concluded this\nPolicy with Us.\nSection B. Benefits\nIMPORTANT: Any claims made under these benefits will impact eligibility for Cumulative Bonus, and\nHealth Checkup.\nWe will cover the Medical Expenses for: We will not cover treatment, costs or expenses for*:\n*The following exclusions apply in addition to the waiting\nperiods and general exclusions specified in Section C-1,2,3\nIn addition to the waiting periods (Section C-1) and\ngeneral exclusions (Section C-2&3), We will also not cover\nexpenses",
      "type": "DEFINITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "DEFINITION"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "20",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 5,
          "end": 7
        },
        {
          "text": "Schedule",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 61,
          "end": 69
        },
        {
          "text": "Us",
          "type": "GPE",
          "start": 105,
          "end": 107
        },
        {
          "text": "Cumulative Bonus",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 205,
          "end": 221
        },
        {
          "text": "the Medical Expenses for: We",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 257,
          "end": 285
        }
      ],
      "confidence": 0.5
    },
    {
      "text": "1. Inpatient Benefits: This section of benefits is applicable when\n• An insured suffers an Accident or Illness, which is covered under this Policy\n• Hospitalisation is necessary & is done for treatment OR\n• Day care treatment is necessary and is done OR\n• Domiciliary treatment is necessary and is done\n1 a. In-Patient Treatment If as per any or all of the Medical references herein\nbelow containing guidelines and protocols for\nThis includes Evidence Based Medicines, the Hospitalisation for\n• Hospital room rent or boarding; treatment under claim is not necessary or the stay\n• Nursing; at the hospital is found unduly long:\n• Intensive Care Unit\n• Medical Practitioners (Fees)  Medical text books,\n• Anesthesia  Standard treatment guidelines as stated in\n• Blood clinical establishment act of Government of\n• Oxygen India,\n• Operation theatre  World Health Organisation (WHO)\n• Surgical appliances; protocols,\n• Medicines, drugs & consumables;  Published guidelines by healthcare",
      "type": "CONDITION",
      "subtypes": [
        "CONDITION",
        "COVERAGE"
      ],
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "1",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 0,
          "end": 1
        },
        {
          "text": "•",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 67,
          "end": 68
        },
        {
          "text": "Accident",
          "type": "LOC",
          "start": 91,
          "end": 99
        },
        {
          "text": "• Day",
          "type": "DATE",
          "start": 205,
          "end": 210
        },
        {
          "text": "•",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 254,
          "end": 255
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 303,
          "end": 304
        },
        {
          "text": "Medical",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 357,
          "end": 364
        },
        {
          "text": "Evidence Based Medicines",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 443,
          "end": 467
        },
        {
          "text": "Hospitalisation",
          "type": "EVENT",
          "start": 473,
          "end": 488
        },
        {
          "text": "• Hospital",
          "type": "ORG",
          "start": 493,
          "end": 503
        },
        {
          "text": "•",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 578,
          "end": 579
        },
        {
          "text": "•",
          "type": "CARDINAL",
          "start": 627,
          "end": 628
        },
        {
          "text": "",
